<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><excuses><excuse><id>1</id><text>
I agree with those who said that in my first statement after I testified   that it was not contrived enough.  I don`t think there is a fancy way to say that I have sinned. It is important for me that everybody who has been hurt to know that the sorrow I feel is genuine. First, the most important- my family, also my friends, my staff, my cabinet, Monica Lewinsky and her family, and the American people. I have asked all for their forgiveness, but I believe that to be forgiven more than sorrow is required. At least two more things. First, genuine repentance and determination to change and repair breaches of my own making.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I agree with those who said that in my first statement after I testified   that it was not contrived enough.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I don`t think there is a fancy way to say that I have sinned.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It is important for me that everybody who has been hurt to know that the sorrow I feel is genuine.</text></sentence><sentence><text>First, the most important- my family, also my friends, my staff, my cabinet, Monica Lewinsky and her family, and the American people.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have asked all for their forgiveness, but I believe that to be forgiven more than sorrow is required.</text></sentence><sentence><text>At least two more things.</text></sentence><sentence><text>First, genuine repentance and determination to change and repair breaches of my own making.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>2</id><text>
Yes, I apologize. Not only do I apologize to secretary Clinton and I hope that we can work together on the independent investigation. I want to apologize to my supporters. It`s not the title of campaign that we`ve run and if I find anybody else involved in this, they will also be fired.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Yes, I apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Not only do I apologize to secretary Clinton and I hope that we can work together on the independent investigation.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I want to apologize to my supporters.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It`s not the title of campaign that we`ve run and if I find anybody else involved in this, they will also be fired.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>3</id><text>
I understand and deserve the feelings of anger and disappointment among my friends and family," Schwarzenegger wrote in a statement. "There are no excuses and I take full responsibility for the hurt I have caused. I have apologized to Maria, my children and my family. I am truly sorry.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I understand and deserve the feelings of anger and disappointment among my friends and family," Schwarzenegger wrote in a statement.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"There are no excuses and I take full responsibility for the hurt I have caused.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have apologized to Maria, my children and my family.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am truly sorry.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>4</id><text>
That was mistake. I am sorry about that. I take responsibility, and I try to be as transparent as I possibly can.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
That was mistake.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am sorry about that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I take responsibility, and I try to be as transparent as I possibly can.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>5</id><text>
I am sorry for the consequences that were unintended and they have many unfortunate impacts on people`s lives. I`ve seen the results of what has happened   in families and in communities. That`s why I chose to make my very first speech a year ago on this issue, because I want to focus the intention on our country and to make the changes we need to make and I want white people to recognize that there is systemic racism. It is in employment.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I am sorry for the consequences that were unintended and they have many unfortunate impacts on people`s lives.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I`ve seen the results of what has happened   in families and in communities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>That`s why I chose to make my very first speech a year ago on this issue, because I want to focus the intention on our country and to make the changes we need to make and I want white people to recognize that there is systemic racism.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It is in employment.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>6</id><text>
This report I received today is a monumental document in more ways than one, (Clinton smiles and holds up a huge bound document as the audience laughs with him) but it is a very, very important piece of America’s history and it will shape America’s future in ways that will make us a more honorable, more successful, and more ethical country.    What this committee learned I would like to review today with a little more detail than Dr. Fadren said because I think it must be engraved on our national memory.   Thousands of government sponsored experiments did take place at hospitals, universities and military bases around our nation.  The goal was to understand the effects of radiation exposure on the human body.    While most of tests were ethical by any standards, some were unethical, not only by today’s standards but by the standards in the time in which they were conducted.  They fail both the test of our national values and the test of humanity.  Informed consent means the doctor tells you the risk of the treatment you are about to undergo.  In too many cases informed consent was withheld.    Americans were kept in the dark about the effects of what was being done to them.  The deception extended beyond the test subjects themselves to encompass their families and the American people as a whole for these experiments were kept secret.  And they were shrouded not for a compelling reason of national security but for the simple fear of embarrassment, and that was wrong. So today on behalf of another generation of American leaders and another generation of American citizens, the United States of America offers a sincere apology to those of our citizens who were subjected to these experiments, and toto their families, and to their communities.  When the government does wrong we have a moral responsibility to admit it.  The duty we owe to one another to tell the truth and to protect our civil citizens from excesses like these is one we can never walk away from.    Our government failed in that duty and it offers an apology to the survivors and their families and to all the American people who must, who must, be able to rely upon the United States to keep its word, to tell the truth and to do the right thing.  Make no mistake, as the committee report says, there are circumstances where compensation is appropriate as a matter of ethics and principle.  I am committed to seeing to it that the United States of America lives up to its responsibility.    Our greatness is measured not only in how we so frequently do right but also how we act when we know we’ve done the wrong thing.  How we confront our mistakes, make our apologies, and take action.   That’s why this morning I signed an executive order instructing every arm and agency of our government that conducts, supports, or regulates research involving human beings to review immediately their procedures in light of recommendations of this report and the best knowledge and standards today and to report back to me by Christmas.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
This report I received today is a monumental document in more ways than one, (Clinton smiles and holds up a huge bound document as the audience laughs with him) but it is a very, very important piece of America’s history and it will shape America’s future in ways that will make us a more honorable, more successful, and more ethical country.</text></sentence><sentence><text>What this committee learned I would like to review today with a little more detail than Dr. Fadren said because I think it must be engraved on our national memory.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Thousands of government sponsored experiments did take place at hospitals, universities and military bases around our nation.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The goal was to understand the effects of radiation exposure on the human body.</text></sentence><sentence><text>While most of tests were ethical by any standards, some were unethical, not only by today’s standards but by the standards in the time in which they were conducted.</text></sentence><sentence><text>They fail both the test of our national values and the test of humanity.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Informed consent means the doctor tells you the risk of the treatment you are about to undergo.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In too many cases informed consent was withheld.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Americans were kept in the dark about the effects of what was being done to them.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The deception extended beyond the test subjects themselves to encompass their families and the American people as a whole for these experiments were kept secret.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And they were shrouded not for a compelling reason of national security but for the simple fear of embarrassment, and that was wrong.</text></sentence><sentence><text>So today on behalf of another generation of American leaders and another generation of American citizens, the United States of America offers a sincere apology to those of our citizens who were subjected to these experiments, and toto their families, and to their communities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>When the government does wrong we have a moral responsibility to admit it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The duty we owe to one another to tell the truth and to protect our civil citizens from excesses like these is one we can never walk away from.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Our government failed in that duty and it offers an apology to the survivors and their families and to all the American people who must, who must, be able to rely upon the United States to keep its word, to tell the truth and to do the right thing.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Make no mistake, as the committee report says, there are circumstances where compensation is appropriate as a matter of ethics and principle.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am committed to seeing to it that the United States of America lives up to its responsibility.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Our greatness is measured not only in how we so frequently do right but also how we act when we know we’ve done the wrong thing.</text></sentence><sentence><text>How we confront our mistakes, make our apologies, and take action.</text></sentence><sentence><text>That’s why this morning I signed an executive order instructing every arm and agency of our government that conducts, supports, or regulates research involving human beings to review immediately their procedures in light of recommendations of this report and the best knowledge and standards today and to report back to me by Christmas.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>7</id><text>
I am here on behalf  of the government of Canada, of prime-minister and all Canadians to apologize for the relocation of the Sayisi Dene. Many of your community members were affected by  the relocation are no longer with us. I would first like to pay tribute to those mothers, fathers, sisters, brothers, and uncles, grandparents and children who passed away before the government of Canada delivered this apology. Today I stand humbly before all of you and offer the following words: We are sorry’’ Sixty years ago, the government of Canada made a tragic and fatal decision that continues to impact all Sayisi Dene First Nation members to this day.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I am here on behalf  of the government of Canada, of prime-minister and all Canadians to apologize for the relocation of the Sayisi Dene.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Many of your community members were affected by  the relocation are no longer with us.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I would first like to pay tribute to those mothers, fathers, sisters, brothers, and uncles, grandparents and children who passed away before the government of Canada delivered this apology.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Today I stand humbly before all of you and offer the following words: We are sorry’’ Sixty years ago, the government of Canada made a tragic and fatal decision that continues to impact all Sayisi Dene First Nation members to this day.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>8</id><text>
I've never said I'm a perfect person, nor pretended to be someone that I'm not. I've said and done things I regret, and the words released today on this more than a decade-old video are one of them. Anyone who knows me knows these words don't reflect who I am. I said it, I was wrong and I apologize. I have traveled the country talking about change for America, but my travels have also changed me. I've spent time with grieving mothers who've lost their children, laid-off workers whose jobs have gone to other countries, and people from all walks of life who just want a better future. I have gotten to know the great people of our country and I've been humbled by the faith they've placed in me. I pledge to be a better man tomorrow, and will never, ever let you down. Let's be honest, we're living in the real world. This is nothing more than a distraction from the important issues we're facing today. We are losing our jobs, we are less safe than we were eight years ago and Washington is totally broken. Hillary Clinton and her kind have run our country into the ground. I've said some foolish things, but there's a big difference between the words and actions of other people. Bill Clinton has actually abused women, and Hillary has bullied, attacked, shamed and intimidated his victims. We will discuss this more in the coming days. See you at the debate on Sunday.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I've never said I'm a perfect person, nor pretended to be someone that I'm not.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I've said and done things I regret, and the words released today on this more than a decade-old video are one of them.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Anyone who knows me knows these words don't reflect who I am.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I said it, I was wrong and I apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have traveled the country talking about change for America, but my travels have also changed me.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I've spent time with grieving mothers who've lost their children, laid-off workers whose jobs have gone to other countries, and people from all walks of life who just want a better future.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have gotten to know the great people of our country and I've been humbled by the faith they've placed in me.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I pledge to be a better man tomorrow, and will never, ever let you down.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Let's be honest, we're living in the real world.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This is nothing more than a distraction from the important issues we're facing today.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We are losing our jobs, we are less safe than we were eight years ago and Washington is totally broken.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Hillary Clinton and her kind have run our country into the ground.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I've said some foolish things, but there's a big difference between the words and actions of other people.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Bill Clinton has actually abused women, and Hillary has bullied, attacked, shamed and intimidated his victims.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We will discuss this more in the coming days.</text></sentence><sentence><text>See you at the debate on Sunday.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>9</id><text>
Mr. Speaker, I stand before you today to offer an apology to former students of Indian residential schools. The treatment of children in Indian residential schools is a sad chapter in our history. In the 1870's, the federal government, partly in order to meet its obligation to educate aboriginal children, began to play a role in the development and administration of these schools. Two primary objectives of the residential schools system were to remove and isolate children from the influence of their homes, families, traditions and cultures, and to assimilate them into the dominant culture. These objectives were based on the assumption aboriginal cultures and spiritual beliefs were inferior and unequal. Indeed, some sought, as it was infamously said, "to kill the Indian in the child."Today, we recognize that this policy of assimilation was wrong, has caused great harm, and has no place in our country. Most schools were operated as "joint ventures" with Anglican, Catholic, Presbyterian or United churches. The government of Canada built an educational system in which very young children were often forcibly removed from their homes, often taken far from their communities. Many were inadequately fed, clothed and housed. All were deprived of the care and nurturing of their parents, grandparents and communities. First Nations, Inuit and Métis languages and cultural practices were prohibited in these schools. Tragically, some of these children died while attending residential schools and others never returned home. The government now recognizes that the consequences of the Indian residential schools policy were profoundly negative and that this policy has had a lasting and damaging impact on aboriginal culture, heritage and language. While some former students have spoken positively about their experiences at residential schools, these stories are far overshadowed by tragic accounts of the emotional, physical and sexual abuse and neglect of helpless children, and their separation from powerless families and communities. The legacy of Indian residential schools has contributed to social problems that continue to exist in many communities today. It has taken extraordinary courage for the thousands of survivors that have come forward to speak publicly about the abuse they suffered. It is a testament to their resilience as individuals and to the strength of their cultures. Regrettably, many former students are not with us today and died never having received a full apology from the government of Canada. The government recognizes that the absence of an apology has been an impediment to healing and reconciliation. Therefore, on behalf of the government of Canada and all Canadians, I stand before you, in this chamber so central to our life as a country, to apologize to aboriginal peoples for Canada's role in the Indian residential schools system. To the approximately 80,000 living former students, and all family members and communities, the government of Canada now recognizes that it was wrong to forcibly remove children from their homes and we apologize for having done this. We now recognize that it was wrong to separate children from rich and vibrant cultures and traditions, that it created a void in many lives and communities, and we apologize for having done this. We now recognize that, in separating children from their families, we undermined the ability of many to adequately parent their own children and sowed the seeds for generations to follow, and we apologize for having done this. We now recognize that, far too often, these institutions gave rise to abuse or neglect and were inadequately controlled, and we apologize for failing to protect you. Not only did you suffer these abuses as children, but as you became parents, you were powerless to protect your own children from suffering the same experience, and for this we are sorry. The burden of this experience has been on your shoulders for far too long. The burden is properly ours as a government, and as a country. There is no place in Canada for the attitudes that inspired the Indian residential schools system to ever again prevail. You have been working on recovering from this experience for a long time and in a very real sense, we are now joining you on this journey. The government of Canada sincerely apologizes and asks the forgiveness of the aboriginal peoples of this country for failing them so profoundly. We are sorry. In moving towards healing, reconciliation and resolution of the sad legacy of Indian residential schools, implementation of the Indian Residential Schools Settlement agreement began on September 19, 2007.Years of work by survivors, communities, and aboriginal organizations culminated in an agreement that gives us a new beginning and an opportunity to move forward together in partnership. A cornerstone of the settlement agreement is the Indian Residential Schools Truth and Reconciliation Commission. This commission presents a unique opportunity to educate all Canadians on the Indian residential schools system. It will be a positive step in forging a new relationship between aboriginal peoples and other Canadians, a relationship based on the knowledge of our shared history, a respect for each other and a desire to move forward together with a renewed understanding that strong families, strong communities and vibrant cultures and traditions will contribute to a stronger Canada for all of us.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Mr. Speaker, I stand before you today to offer an apology to former students of Indian residential schools.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The treatment of children in Indian residential schools is a sad chapter in our history.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In the 1870's, the federal government, partly in order to meet its obligation to educate aboriginal children, began to play a role in the development and administration of these schools.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Two primary objectives of the residential schools system were to remove and isolate children from the influence of their homes, families, traditions and cultures, and to assimilate them into the dominant culture.</text></sentence><sentence><text>These objectives were based on the assumption aboriginal cultures and spiritual beliefs were inferior and unequal.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Indeed, some sought, as it was infamously said, "to kill the Indian in the child.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"Today, we recognize that this policy of assimilation was wrong, has caused great harm, and has no place in our country.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Most schools were operated as "joint ventures" with Anglican, Catholic, Presbyterian or United churches.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The government of Canada built an educational system in which very young children were often forcibly removed from their homes, often taken far from their communities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Many were inadequately fed, clothed and housed.</text></sentence><sentence><text>All were deprived of the care and nurturing of their parents, grandparents and communities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>First Nations, Inuit and Métis languages and cultural practices were prohibited in these schools.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Tragically, some of these children died while attending residential schools and others never returned home.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The government now recognizes that the consequences of the Indian residential schools policy were profoundly negative and that this policy has had a lasting and damaging impact on aboriginal culture, heritage and language.</text></sentence><sentence><text>While some former students have spoken positively about their experiences at residential schools, these stories are far overshadowed by tragic accounts of the emotional, physical and sexual abuse and neglect of helpless children, and their separation from powerless families and communities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The legacy of Indian residential schools has contributed to social problems that continue to exist in many communities today.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It has taken extraordinary courage for the thousands of survivors that have come forward to speak publicly about the abuse they suffered.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It is a testament to their resilience as individuals and to the strength of their cultures.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Regrettably, many former students are not with us today and died never having received a full apology from the government of Canada.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The government recognizes that the absence of an apology has been an impediment to healing and reconciliation.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Therefore, on behalf of the government of Canada and all Canadians, I stand before you, in this chamber so central to our life as a country, to apologize to aboriginal peoples for Canada's role in the Indian residential schools system.</text></sentence><sentence><text>To the approximately 80,000 living former students, and all family members and communities, the government of Canada now recognizes that it was wrong to forcibly remove children from their homes and we apologize for having done this.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We now recognize that it was wrong to separate children from rich and vibrant cultures and traditions, that it created a void in many lives and communities, and we apologize for having done this.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We now recognize that, in separating children from their families, we undermined the ability of many to adequately parent their own children and sowed the seeds for generations to follow, and we apologize for having done this.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We now recognize that, far too often, these institutions gave rise to abuse or neglect and were inadequately controlled, and we apologize for failing to protect you.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Not only did you suffer these abuses as children, but as you became parents, you were powerless to protect your own children from suffering the same experience, and for this we are sorry.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The burden of this experience has been on your shoulders for far too long.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The burden is properly ours as a government, and as a country.</text></sentence><sentence><text>There is no place in Canada for the attitudes that inspired the Indian residential schools system to ever again prevail.</text></sentence><sentence><text>You have been working on recovering from this experience for a long time and in a very real sense, we are now joining you on this journey.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The government of Canada sincerely apologizes and asks the forgiveness of the aboriginal peoples of this country for failing them so profoundly.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We are sorry.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In moving towards healing, reconciliation and resolution of the sad legacy of Indian residential schools, implementation of the Indian Residential Schools Settlement agreement began on September 19, 2007.Years of work by survivors, communities, and aboriginal organizations culminated in an agreement that gives us a new beginning and an opportunity to move forward together in partnership.</text></sentence><sentence><text>A cornerstone of the settlement agreement is the Indian Residential Schools Truth and Reconciliation Commission.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This commission presents a unique opportunity to educate all Canadians on the Indian residential schools system.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It will be a positive step in forging a new relationship between aboriginal peoples and other Canadians, a relationship based on the knowledge of our shared history, a respect for each other and a desire to move forward together with a renewed understanding that strong families, strong communities and vibrant cultures and traditions will contribute to a stronger Canada for all of us.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>10</id><text>
To be clear, the picture was of me, and I sent it. I'm deeply sorry for the pain this has caused my wife, and our family, my constituents, my friends, my supporters and my staff," he said. "I lied because I was ashamed at what I had done, and I didn't want to get caught." Weiner eventually resigned from his post after his online antics.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
To be clear, the picture was of me, and I sent it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I'm deeply sorry for the pain this has caused my wife, and our family, my constituents, my friends, my supporters and my staff," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I lied because I was ashamed at what I had done, and I didn't want to get caught.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" Weiner eventually resigned from his post after his online antics.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>11</id><text>
The Secretary of State for Northern Ireland is publishing the report of the Saville inquiry - the tribunal set up by the previous government to investigate the tragic events of 30 January 1972, a day more commonly known as Bloody Sunday. We have acted in good faith by publishing the tribunal's findings as soon as possible after the general election. Mr Speaker, I am deeply patriotic. I never want to believe anything bad about our country. I never want to call into question the behaviour of our soldiers and our army, who I believe to be the finest in the world. And I have seen for myself the very difficult and dangerous circumstances in which we ask our soldiers to serve. But the conclusions of this report are absolutely clear. There is no doubt, there is nothing equivocal, there are no ambiguities. What happened on Bloody Sunday was both unjustified and unjustifiable. It was wrong.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
The Secretary of State for Northern Ireland is publishing the report of the Saville inquiry - the tribunal set up by the previous government to investigate the tragic events of 30 January 1972, a day more commonly known as Bloody Sunday.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We have acted in good faith by publishing the tribunal's findings as soon as possible after the general election.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Mr Speaker, I am deeply patriotic.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I never want to believe anything bad about our country.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I never want to call into question the behaviour of our soldiers and our army, who I believe to be the finest in the world.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And I have seen for myself the very difficult and dangerous circumstances in which we ask our soldiers to serve.</text></sentence><sentence><text>But the conclusions of this report are absolutely clear.</text></sentence><sentence><text>There is no doubt, there is nothing equivocal, there are no ambiguities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>What happened on Bloody Sunday was both unjustified and unjustifiable.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was wrong.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>12</id><text>
“I understand people’s sensitivities. Nobody meant anything. It was not meant to offend you or hurt you in any fashion. I’m sorry people were offended. It was not meant that way. In hindsight, I should have picked something else. It never crossed my mind for a split second that I was doing something wrong.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I understand people’s sensitivities.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Nobody meant anything.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was not meant to offend you or hurt you in any fashion.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I’m sorry people were offended.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was not meant that way.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In hindsight, I should have picked something else.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It never crossed my mind for a split second that I was doing something wrong.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>13</id><text>
At a point in every person's life, one has to look deeply into the mirror of one's soul and decide one's unique truth in the world, not as we may want to see it or hope to see it, but as it is. And so, my truth is that I am a gay American. … Shamefully, I engaged in an adult consensual affair with another man, which violates my bonds of matrimony. It was wrong. It was foolish. It was inexcusable. And for this, I ask the forgiveness and the grace of my wife.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
At a point in every person's life, one has to look deeply into the mirror of one's soul and decide one's unique truth in the world, not as we may want to see it or hope to see it, but as it is.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And so, my truth is that I am a gay American.</text></sentence><sentence><text>… Shamefully, I engaged in an adult consensual affair with another man, which violates my bonds of matrimony.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was wrong.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was foolish.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was inexcusable.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And for this, I ask the forgiveness and the grace of my wife.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>14</id><text>
This was a very serious sin in my past for which I am, of course, completely responsible. Several years ago, I asked for and received forgiveness from God and my wife in confession and marriage counseling. Out of respect for my family, I will keep my discussion of the matter there - with God and them. But I certainly offer my deep and sincere apologies to all I have disappointed and let down in any way.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
This was a very serious sin in my past for which I am, of course, completely responsible.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Several years ago, I asked for and received forgiveness from God and my wife in confession and marriage counseling.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Out of respect for my family, I will keep my discussion of the matter there - with God and them.</text></sentence><sentence><text>But I certainly offer my deep and sincere apologies to all I have disappointed and let down in any way.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>15</id><text>
I am deeply sorry that I did not live up to what was expected of me. I will try once again outside of politics to serve the common good. … Our greatest glory consists not in never falling, but in rising every time we fall.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I am deeply sorry that I did not live up to what was expected of me.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I will try once again outside of politics to serve the common good.</text></sentence><sentence><text>… Our greatest glory consists not in never falling, but in rising every time we fall.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>16</id><text>
I’m here today to again apologize for the personal mistakes I have made and the embarrassment I have caused. I make this apology to my neighbors and constituents, but I make it particularly to my wife Huma. I had hoped to be able to continue the work that the citizens of my district had elected me to do, to fight for the middle class and those struggling to make it. Unfortunately, the distraction I have created has made that impossible.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I’m here today to again apologize for the personal mistakes I have made and the embarrassment I have caused.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I make this apology to my neighbors and constituents, but I make it particularly to my wife Huma.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I had hoped to be able to continue the work that the citizens of my district had elected me to do, to fight for the middle class and those struggling to make it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Unfortunately, the distraction I have created has made that impossible.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>17</id><text>
The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador, on behalf of the citizens of the province, apologizes to the Inuit of Nutak and Hebron for the way in which the decision to close those communities was made and for the difficulties experienced by them and their descendants as a result of the closures”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador, on behalf of the citizens of the province, apologizes to the Inuit of Nutak and Hebron for the way in which the decision to close those communities was made and for the difficulties experienced by them and their descendants as a result of the closures”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>18</id><text>
a)	‘’On behalf of the people of South Carolina, I apologize for decades of suffering and pain caused by eugenics," Hodges said Wednesday.
b)	"Today, I want to acknowledge the great injustice done to more than 250 men and women when the State of South Carolina permitted involuntary sterilization for decades.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
a)	‘’On behalf of the people of South Carolina, I apologize for decades of suffering and pain caused by eugenics," Hodges said Wednesday.</text></sentence><sentence><text>b)	"Today, I want to acknowledge the great injustice done to more than 250 men and women when the State of South Carolina permitted involuntary sterilization for decades.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>19</id><text>
This evening I let my emotions get the best of me when listening to the president’s remarks regarding the coverage of illegal immigrants in the health care bill,” Wilson said. “While I disagree with the president’s statement, my comments were inappropriate and regrettable.  I extend sincere apologies to the president for this lack of civility.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
This evening I let my emotions get the best of me when listening to the president’s remarks regarding the coverage of illegal immigrants in the health care bill,” Wilson said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“While I disagree with the president’s statement, my comments were inappropriate and regrettable.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I extend sincere apologies to the president for this lack of civility.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>20</id><text>
Unfortunately, I was blind to how arrogant and self-centered I became," Ensign said in a 13-minute farewell. "This is how dangerous the feelings of power and adulation can be."Ensign, 53, leaves office today after admitting two years ago to an extramarital affair with former campaign aide Cindy Hampton, his wife's best friend. The affair spawned multiple investigations, including one by the Senate Ethics Committee that appeared to be coming to a head when Ensign said he was resigning to relieve pressure on his family.Gov. Brian Sandoval has named Rep. Dean Heller, R-Nev., to finish Ensign's second term through 2012. Vice President Joe Biden will swear Heller into office Monday , according to Heller's staff. In his farewell speech, which he delivered to a chamber empty of other senators, Ensign did not speak directly about the extramarital affair but focused instead on his failure to avoid being swept up in his own self-importance. Ensign has insisted he broke no law nor Senate rule in his extramarital affair and was innocent of subsequent allegations of corruption leveled by Hampton's husband, Doug, who also was a friend and former staff member. However, he apologized to his colleagues for any stress he caused them."I know that many of you were put in difficult situations because of me, and for that I sincerely apologize," he said. Ensign offered a public apology as well for having harshly judged two former colleagues -- Sens. Larry Craig, R-Idaho, and Ted Stevens, R-Alaska -- after they were caught up in their own corruption scandals. Ensign said he spoke to both of them weeks after his public calls for them to resign, saying he was wrong to judge them, and they forgave him."When I announced my personal failure two years ago, Larry Craig was one of the first to call. I truly cannot tell you how much that meant to me," he said. Ensign said he owed "a humble thank you" to many people -- campaign volunteers, staff, donors and his Senate colleagues -- for helping him achieve several "proud successes" for Nevada. Ensign focused particularly on legislation he advocated to protect Lake Tahoe and the Southern Nevada Public Lands Management Act, which yielded $3 billion for the state through auctions of public land in the Las Vegas Valley and created an endowment for public schools. He spoke proudly of authoring, with Sen. Tom Carper, D-Del., a bipartisan provision in last year's health care overhaul law that would allow lower insurance premiums to people with healthy lifestyles. Ensign also thanked Sen. Harry Reid, D-Nev., for the "true friendship" that developed between them as Senate colleagues working on behalf of Nevada. After delivering his farewell address, Ensign met with Reid in his Capitol office. Reid issued a brief statement later offering his best wishes to Ensign and his family."I have valued John Ensign's partnership over the years as we worked together to improve our state," Reid said. "As John enters the next chapter in his life and departs from the United States Senate, I wish him and his family well as they work through this difficult time."Ensign ended his speech by thanking God. He said he was encouraged not to mention God at the risk of appearing hypocritical considering his failings."I would argue that I have not mentioned him enough," Ensign said. "I'm glad that the Lord not only forgives, but he actually likes it when we give him thanks. So, Lord, thank you for all that you've done in my life. I hope that I can do better in the future.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Unfortunately, I was blind to how arrogant and self-centered I became," Ensign said in a 13-minute farewell.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"This is how dangerous the feelings of power and adulation can be.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"Ensign, 53, leaves office today after admitting two years ago to an extramarital affair with former campaign aide Cindy Hampton, his wife's best friend.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The affair spawned multiple investigations, including one by the Senate Ethics Committee that appeared to be coming to a head when Ensign said he was resigning to relieve pressure on his family.Gov.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Brian Sandoval has named Rep. Dean Heller, R-Nev., to finish Ensign's second term through 2012.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Vice President Joe Biden will swear Heller into office Monday , according to Heller's staff.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In his farewell speech, which he delivered to a chamber empty of other senators, Ensign did not speak directly about the extramarital affair but focused instead on his failure to avoid being swept up in his own self-importance.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Ensign has insisted he broke no law nor Senate rule in his extramarital affair and was innocent of subsequent allegations of corruption leveled by Hampton's husband, Doug, who also was a friend and former staff member.</text></sentence><sentence><text>However, he apologized to his colleagues for any stress he caused them.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I know that many of you were put in difficult situations because of me, and for that I sincerely apologize," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Ensign offered a public apology as well for having harshly judged two former colleagues -- Sens.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Larry Craig, R-Idaho, and Ted Stevens, R-Alaska -- after they were caught up in their own corruption scandals.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Ensign said he spoke to both of them weeks after his public calls for them to resign, saying he was wrong to judge them, and they forgave him.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"When I announced my personal failure two years ago, Larry Craig was one of the first to call.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I truly cannot tell you how much that meant to me," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Ensign said he owed "a humble thank you" to many people -- campaign volunteers, staff, donors and his Senate colleagues -- for helping him achieve several "proud successes" for Nevada.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Ensign focused particularly on legislation he advocated to protect Lake Tahoe and the Southern Nevada Public Lands Management Act, which yielded $3 billion for the state through auctions of public land in the Las Vegas Valley and created an endowment for public schools.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He spoke proudly of authoring, with Sen. Tom Carper, D-Del., a bipartisan provision in last year's health care overhaul law that would allow lower insurance premiums to people with healthy lifestyles.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Ensign also thanked Sen. Harry Reid, D-Nev., for the "true friendship" that developed between them as Senate colleagues working on behalf of Nevada.</text></sentence><sentence><text>After delivering his farewell address, Ensign met with Reid in his Capitol office.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Reid issued a brief statement later offering his best wishes to Ensign and his family.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I have valued John Ensign's partnership over the years as we worked together to improve our state," Reid said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"As John enters the next chapter in his life and departs from the United States Senate, I wish him and his family well as they work through this difficult time.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"Ensign ended his speech by thanking God.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He said he was encouraged not to mention God at the risk of appearing hypocritical considering his failings.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I would argue that I have not mentioned him enough," Ensign said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I'm glad that the Lord not only forgives, but he actually likes it when we give him thanks.</text></sentence><sentence><text>So, Lord, thank you for all that you've done in my life.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I hope that I can do better in the future.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>21</id><text>
If it is [offensive], I apologize. It was not intended to be a racial slur. I wasn’t intending to say a racial slur at all.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
If it is [offensive], I apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was not intended to be a racial slur.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I wasn’t intending to say a racial slur at all.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>22</id><text>
When Ohio State’s former president joked at a meeting last year that Notre Dame wasn’t allowed in the Big Ten Conference because “those damn Catholics” couldn’t be trusted, he should have just headed straight to the confession booth. The gaffe-prone Gee, like a guilty altar boy, was quick to ask for forgiveness. “The comments I made were just plain wrong, and in no way do they reflect what the university stands for. They were a poor attempt at humor and entirely inappropriate. There is no excuse for this, and I am deeply sorry.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
When Ohio State’s former president joked at a meeting last year that Notre Dame wasn’t allowed in the Big Ten Conference because “those damn Catholics” couldn’t be trusted, he should have just headed straight to the confession booth.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The gaffe-prone Gee, like a guilty altar boy, was quick to ask for forgiveness.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“The comments I made were just plain wrong, and in no way do they reflect what the university stands for.</text></sentence><sentence><text>They were a poor attempt at humor and entirely inappropriate.</text></sentence><sentence><text>There is no excuse for this, and I am deeply sorry.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>23</id><text>
I'm sorry the financial crisis has had such a devastating impact for our country. I'm sorry about the millions of people, average Americans, who lost their homes. And I'm sorry that our management teams, starting with me, like so many others could not see the unprecedented market collapse that lay before us.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I'm sorry the financial crisis has had such a devastating impact for our country.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I'm sorry about the millions of people, average Americans, who lost their homes.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And I'm sorry that our management teams, starting with me, like so many others could not see the unprecedented market collapse that lay before us.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>24</id><text>
I sincerely apologize to customers and the public for the company's failure to comply with legal and regulatory requirements in Japan and we regret the concern and inconvenience caused. I would like to reinforce Citigroup's commitment to Japan and our long-term commitment to our customers here. Citigroup has been in Japan for more than 100 years and we will take all necessary steps to ensure business is properly conducted.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I sincerely apologize to customers and the public for the company's failure to comply with legal and regulatory requirements in Japan and we regret the concern and inconvenience caused.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I would like to reinforce Citigroup's commitment to Japan and our long-term commitment to our customers here.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Citigroup has been in Japan for more than 100 years and we will take all necessary steps to ensure business is properly conducted.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>25</id><text>
We regret very much the embarrassment that's been caused to you," the US leader said during the call. Baroness Thatcher was angered that she was not consulted before the Americans invaded a Commonwealth state.
United States troops were sent to Grenada in 1983 to topple the Caribbean island's Marxist regime. While US forces were still in action, the president phoned Lady Thatcher to explain the action he had taken. "If I were there, Margaret," he said, "I'd throw my hat in the door before I came in." The saying refers to a Civil War-era practice in which a visitor might throw his hat into a room before entering - if he was unwelcome, it might be thrown out again or even shot at. "There's no need for that," Lady Thatcher replied. Reagan continued: "We regret very much the embarrassment that's been caused to you, and I would like to tell you what the story is from our end." He explained that military commanders only had "a matter of hours" to mobilise the troops and that he was prevented from discussing it with her sooner because of security fears. "We were greatly concerned because of a problem here - and not at your end at all - but here. We've had a nagging problem of a loose source, a leak," he told her.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
We regret very much the embarrassment that's been caused to you," the US leader said during the call.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Baroness Thatcher was angered that she was not consulted before the Americans invaded a Commonwealth state.</text></sentence><sentence><text>United States troops were sent to Grenada in 1983 to topple the Caribbean island's Marxist regime.</text></sentence><sentence><text>While US forces were still in action, the president phoned Lady Thatcher to explain the action he had taken.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"If I were there, Margaret," he said, "I'd throw my hat in the door before I came in.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" The saying refers to a Civil War-era practice in which a visitor might throw his hat into a room before entering - if he was unwelcome, it might be thrown out again or even shot at.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"There's no need for that," Lady Thatcher replied.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Reagan continued: "We regret very much the embarrassment that's been caused to you, and I would like to tell you what the story is from our end.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" He explained that military commanders only had "a matter of hours" to mobilise the troops and that he was prevented from discussing it with her sooner because of security fears.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"We were greatly concerned because of a problem here - and not at your end at all - but here.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We've had a nagging problem of a loose source, a leak," he told her.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>26</id><text>
“I want to call to your attention the fact that I've taken time to go through the integrity commissioner's report on a formal complaint lodged against me while I was mayor of this great city.
“I'm aware of my hurtful nature of my comments and the fact that they are absolutely unacceptable.
“I understand the concerns brought forward in the report including the standards set out by the Ontario Human Rights Code.
“Mr. Mayor, members of council, I'm deeply ashamed of what I said and I recognize that they bring discredit to both myself and council as a whole. I wish to offer my heartfelt apology for my words and actions. Thank you Madame Speaker.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I want to call to your attention the fact that I've taken time to go through the integrity commissioner's report on a formal complaint lodged against me while I was mayor of this great city.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I'm aware of my hurtful nature of my comments and the fact that they are absolutely unacceptable.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I understand the concerns brought forward in the report including the standards set out by the Ontario Human Rights Code.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“Mr.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Mayor, members of council, I'm deeply ashamed of what I said and I recognize that they bring discredit to both myself and council as a whole.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I wish to offer my heartfelt apology for my words and actions.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Thank you Madame Speaker.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>27</id><text>
“Five years ago, when I was first elected to Congress I was invited on a trip to Scotland. I found out later that it was paid for by a corrupt lobbyist,” Feeney said in the spot, in which he was seated at a kitchen table. “It was a rookie mistake and I did everything I could to make it right. I reported it to the ethics committee and I paid the money back. I embarrassed myself, I embarrassed you and, for that, I’m very sorry. I’m Tom Feeney and I approve this message because public service means about being honest, even when you make a mistake.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“Five years ago, when I was first elected to Congress I was invited on a trip to Scotland.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I found out later that it was paid for by a corrupt lobbyist,” Feeney said in the spot, in which he was seated at a kitchen table.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“It was a rookie mistake and I did everything I could to make it right.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I reported it to the ethics committee and I paid the money back.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I embarrassed myself, I embarrassed you and, for that, I’m very sorry.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I’m Tom Feeney and I approve this message because public service means about being honest, even when you make a mistake.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>28</id><text>
Under mounting pressure, Cicilline recently apologized for his managerial missteps in a letter to supporters and in a television interview, all but acknowledging that he hadn’t been completely straightforward in revealing the fiscal problems the city faced. hould have been much clearer the challenge the city faces,” Cicilline told a local TV station this month. “I should have been much louder in the consequences of the state cuts and to the extent anything I did contributed to the challenge the city faces, I’m sorry for that and I accept full responsibility for it.” “I understand now why people feel I misled them and I understand why people feel betrayed and it’s important for me to address that,” he added.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Under mounting pressure, Cicilline recently apologized for his managerial missteps in a letter to supporters and in a television interview, all but acknowledging that he hadn’t been completely straightforward in revealing the fiscal problems the city faced.</text></sentence><sentence><text>hould have been much clearer the challenge the city faces,” Cicilline told a local TV station this month.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I should have been much louder in the consequences of the state cuts and to the extent anything I did contributed to the challenge the city faces, I’m sorry for that and I accept full responsibility for it.” “I understand now why people feel I misled them and I understand why people feel betrayed and it’s important for me to address that,” he added.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>29</id><text>
To my fellow Americans and to everyone else who has seen this email I forwarded and was offended by my action, I humbly apologize and ask for your forgiveness of my unwise behavior. 'I say unwise because at the time I received and forwarded the email, I didn't stop to think about the historic implications and other examples of how this could be offensive. 'I am an imperfect Christian lady who tries her best to live a Christ-like honoring life. I would never do anything to intentionally harm or berate others regardless of ethnicity. Everyone who knows me knows that to be true.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
To my fellow Americans and to everyone else who has seen this email I forwarded and was offended by my action, I humbly apologize and ask for your forgiveness of my unwise behavior.</text></sentence><sentence><text>'I say unwise because at the time I received and forwarded the email, I didn't stop to think about the historic implications and other examples of how this could be offensive.</text></sentence><sentence><text>'I am an imperfect Christian lady who tries her best to live a Christ-like honoring life.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I would never do anything to intentionally harm or berate others regardless of ethnicity.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Everyone who knows me knows that to be true.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>30</id><text>
What I would say to those people is, I am extremely sorry because we wanted to do everything we can to help them leave. It is a very difficult picture in Libya. This is not an easy situation.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
What I would say to those people is, I am extremely sorry because we wanted to do everything we can to help them leave.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It is a very difficult picture in Libya.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This is not an easy situation.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>31</id><text>
Politicians and political parties can only grow stronger by acknowledging when they get it wrong and by facing up to their mistakes. So I now apologize sincerely on behalf of my party for the disastrous decision to go to war in Iraq in March 2003. "That apology is owed first of all to the people of Iraq. Hundreds of thousands of lives have been lost and the country is still living with the devastating consequences of the war and the forces it unleashed. They have paid the greatest price for the most serious foreign policy calamity of the last 60 years. The apology is also owed to the families of those soldiers who died in Iraq or who have returned home injured or incapacitated. They did their duty but it was in a conflict they should never have been sent to. Finally, it is an apology to the millions of British citizens who feel our democracy was traduced and undermined by the way in which the decision to go to war was taken on the basic of secret ‘I will be with you, whatever’ understandings given to the US president that have now been publicly exposed.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Politicians and political parties can only grow stronger by acknowledging when they get it wrong and by facing up to their mistakes.</text></sentence><sentence><text>So I now apologize sincerely on behalf of my party for the disastrous decision to go to war in Iraq in March 2003.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"That apology is owed first of all to the people of Iraq.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Hundreds of thousands of lives have been lost and the country is still living with the devastating consequences of the war and the forces it unleashed.</text></sentence><sentence><text>They have paid the greatest price for the most serious foreign policy calamity of the last 60 years.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The apology is also owed to the families of those soldiers who died in Iraq or who have returned home injured or incapacitated.</text></sentence><sentence><text>They did their duty but it was in a conflict they should never have been sent to.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Finally, it is an apology to the millions of British citizens who feel our democracy was traduced and undermined by the way in which the decision to go to war was taken on the basic of secret ‘I will be with you, whatever’ understandings given to the US president that have now been publicly exposed.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>33</id><text>
Hague made his announcement to a sparsely filled House of Commons. He described the payment as “full and final”: “The British government recognizes that Kenyans were subject to torture and other forms of ill treatment at the hands of the colonial administration. The British government sincerely regrets that these abuses took place.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Hague made his announcement to a sparsely filled House of Commons.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He described the payment as “full and final”: “The British government recognizes that Kenyans were subject to torture and other forms of ill treatment at the hands of the colonial administration.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The British government sincerely regrets that these abuses took place.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>34</id><text>
“I know the American people are tired of it,” Obama said at a White House news conference. “I apologize that you have to go through this stuff every three months, it seems like. And Lord knows I’m tired of it.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I know the American people are tired of it,” Obama said at a White House news conference.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I apologize that you have to go through this stuff every three months, it seems like.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And Lord knows I’m tired of it.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>35</id><text>
Colorado Gov. John Hickenlooper, said, “On behalf of the State of Colorado, I want to apologize… To the runners, to the Tribal Leaders, and to all of the Indigenous people—and the proud and painful legacy you all represent—On behalf of the good, peaceful and loving people of Colorado, I want to say, I am sorry for the atrocity that our government and its agents visited upon your ancestors.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Colorado Gov.</text></sentence><sentence><text>John Hickenlooper, said, “On behalf of the State of Colorado, I want to apologize… To the runners, to the Tribal Leaders, and to all of the Indigenous people—and the proud and painful legacy you all represent—On behalf of the good, peaceful and loving people of Colorado, I want to say, I am sorry for the atrocity that our government and its agents visited upon your ancestors.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>36</id><text>
“Let us begin by expressing our profound sorrow for what this agency has done in the past. Just like you, when we think of these misdeeds and their tragic consequences, our hearts break and our grief is as pure and complete as yours. We desperately wish that we could change this history, but of course we cannot. On behalf of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, I extend this formal apology to Indian people for the historical conduct of this agency.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“Let us begin by expressing our profound sorrow for what this agency has done in the past.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Just like you, when we think of these misdeeds and their tragic consequences, our hearts break and our grief is as pure and complete as yours.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We desperately wish that we could change this history, but of course we cannot.</text></sentence><sentence><text>On behalf of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, I extend this formal apology to Indian people for the historical conduct of this agency.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>37</id><text>
I have said we are sorry and I say it again," he said after talks with Ghanaian president John Agyekum Kufuor. The most important thing was "to remember what happened in the past, to condemn it and say why it was entirely unacceptable," Mr Blair said.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I have said we are sorry and I say it again," he said after talks with Ghanaian president John Agyekum Kufuor.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The most important thing was "to remember what happened in the past, to condemn it and say why it was entirely unacceptable," Mr Blair said.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>38</id><text>
It was unacceptable and we’ve sent our apologies directly to the journalists, and we’ll make sure that this doesn’t happen again.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
It was unacceptable and we’ve sent our apologies directly to the journalists, and we’ll make sure that this doesn’t happen again.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>39</id><text>
I have acted in a way that violates my obligations to my family and that violates my -- or any -- sense of right and wrong. I apologize first, and most importantly, to my family. I apologize to the public, whom I promised better.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I have acted in a way that violates my obligations to my family and that violates my -- or any -- sense of right and wrong.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize first, and most importantly, to my family.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize to the public, whom I promised better.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>40</id><text>
First, please let me apologize to my family, friends, staff and fellow Idahoans for the cloud placed over Idaho. I did nothing wrong at the Minneapolis airport. I regret my decision to plead guilty and the sadness that decision has brought to my wife, family, friends, staff, and fellow Idahoans. For that I apologize... Let me be clear. I am not gay and never have been. In June, I overreacted and made a poor decision. While I was not involved in any inappropriate conduct at the Minneapolis airport or anywhere else, I chose to plead guilty to a lesser charge in the hope of making it go away. I did not seek any counsel, either from an attorney, staff, friends, or family. That was a mistake, and I deeply regret it. Because of that, I have now retained counsel and I am asking my counsel to review this matter and to advise me on how to proceed. For a moment, I want to put my state of mind into context on June 11. For eight months leading up to June, my family and I had been relentlessly and viciously harassed by the Idaho Statesman. If you've seen today's paper, you know why. Let me be clear: I am not gay and never have been. Still, without a shred of truth or evidence to the contrary, the Statesman has engaged in this witch hunt. In pleading guilty, I overreacted in Minneapolis, because of the stress of the Idaho Statesman's investigation and the rumors it has fueled around Idaho. Again, that overreaction was a mistake, and I apologize for my misjudgment. Furthermore, I should not have kept this arrest to myself, and should have told my family and friends about it. I wasn't eager to share this failure, but I should have done so anyway. I love my wife, family, friends, staff and Idaho. I love serving Idaho in Congress. Over the years, I have accomplished a lot for Idaho, and I hope Idahoans will allow me to continue to do that. There are still goals I would like to accomplish, and I believe I can still be an effective leader for Idaho. Next month, I will announce, as planned, whether or not I will seek re-election. As an elected official, I fully realize that my life is open for public criticism and scrutiny, and I take full responsibility for the mistake in judgment I made in attempting to handle this matter myself. It is clear, though, that through my actions I have brought a cloud over Idaho. For that, I ask the people of Idaho for their forgiveness.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
First, please let me apologize to my family, friends, staff and fellow Idahoans for the cloud placed over Idaho.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I did nothing wrong at the Minneapolis airport.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I regret my decision to plead guilty and the sadness that decision has brought to my wife, family, friends, staff, and fellow Idahoans.</text></sentence><sentence><text>For that I apologize... Let me be clear.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am not gay and never have been.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In June, I overreacted and made a poor decision.</text></sentence><sentence><text>While I was not involved in any inappropriate conduct at the Minneapolis airport or anywhere else, I chose to plead guilty to a lesser charge in the hope of making it go away.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I did not seek any counsel, either from an attorney, staff, friends, or family.</text></sentence><sentence><text>That was a mistake, and I deeply regret it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Because of that, I have now retained counsel and I am asking my counsel to review this matter and to advise me on how to proceed.</text></sentence><sentence><text>For a moment, I want to put my state of mind into context on June 11.</text></sentence><sentence><text>For eight months leading up to June, my family and I had been relentlessly and viciously harassed by the Idaho Statesman.</text></sentence><sentence><text>If you've seen today's paper, you know why.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Let me be clear: I am not gay and never have been.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Still, without a shred of truth or evidence to the contrary, the Statesman has engaged in this witch hunt.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In pleading guilty, I overreacted in Minneapolis, because of the stress of the Idaho Statesman's investigation and the rumors it has fueled around Idaho.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Again, that overreaction was a mistake, and I apologize for my misjudgment.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Furthermore, I should not have kept this arrest to myself, and should have told my family and friends about it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I wasn't eager to share this failure, but I should have done so anyway.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I love my wife, family, friends, staff and Idaho.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I love serving Idaho in Congress.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Over the years, I have accomplished a lot for Idaho, and I hope Idahoans will allow me to continue to do that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>There are still goals I would like to accomplish, and I believe I can still be an effective leader for Idaho.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Next month, I will announce, as planned, whether or not I will seek re-election.</text></sentence><sentence><text>As an elected official, I fully realize that my life is open for public criticism and scrutiny, and I take full responsibility for the mistake in judgment I made in attempting to handle this matter myself.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It is clear, though, that through my actions I have brought a cloud over Idaho.</text></sentence><sentence><text>For that, I ask the people of Idaho for their forgiveness.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>41</id><text>
”I wanted to honor Strom Thurmond, the man, who was turning 100 years old. He certainly has been a legend in the Senate both in terms of his service and the length of his service. It was certainly not intended to endorse his segregationist policies that he might have been advocating or was advocating 54 years ago. But obviously, I am sorry for my words, they were poorly chosen and insensitive and I regret the way it has been interpreted.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
”I wanted to honor Strom Thurmond, the man, who was turning 100 years old.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He certainly has been a legend in the Senate both in terms of his service and the length of his service.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was certainly not intended to endorse his segregationist policies that he might have been advocating or was advocating 54 years ago.</text></sentence><sentence><text>But obviously, I am sorry for my words, they were poorly chosen and insensitive and I regret the way it has been interpreted.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>42</id><text>
“I’m apologizing for the conduct that it was alleged that I did, and I say I am sorry.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I’m apologizing for the conduct that it was alleged that I did, and I say I am sorry.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>43</id><text>
“I deeply regret any offense my remark in the New York Observer might have caused anyone.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I deeply regret any offense my remark in the New York Observer might have caused anyone.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>44</id><text>
If the remarks on the tape left anyone with the impression that I was disrespectful to either Gov. Cuomo or Italian-Americans, then I deeply regret it. At the time the conversation was held, there had been some political give and take between myself and the governor and I meant simply to imply that Gov. Cuomo is a tough, worthy competitor.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
If the remarks on the tape left anyone with the impression that I was disrespectful to either Gov.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Cuomo or Italian-Americans, then I deeply regret it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>At the time the conversation was held, there had been some political give and take between myself and the governor and I meant simply to imply that Gov.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Cuomo is a tough, worthy competitor.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>45</id><text>
It was a complete accident," Ford said. "I do sincerely apologize to you, Coun. McConnell.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
It was a complete accident," Ford said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I do sincerely apologize to you, Coun.</text></sentence><sentence><text>McConnell.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>46</id><text>
I wholly retract my statements and apologize to Mr. Dale without reservation for what I said," Ford said in a statement. "There is absolutely no basis for the statement I made about Daniel Dale taking pictures of children or any insinuations I made," Ford added. The mayor retracted other statements, including that Dale had been found "lurking" or "leering" near his property. Dale accepted the apology and dropped his legal action against Ford.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I wholly retract my statements and apologize to Mr. Dale without reservation for what I said," Ford said in a statement.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"There is absolutely no basis for the statement I made about Daniel Dale taking pictures of children or any insinuations I made," Ford added.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The mayor retracted other statements, including that Dale had been found "lurking" or "leering" near his property.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Dale accepted the apology and dropped his legal action against Ford.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>47</id><text>
I want to apologize for my graphic remarks this morning.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I want to apologize for my graphic remarks this morning.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>48</id><text>
I'm sure you understand this has been a very stressful week for myself and my family, but that doesn't justify using the terminology I did in describing the media," Ford said. "I sincerely apologize to each and every one of you.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I'm sure you understand this has been a very stressful week for myself and my family, but that doesn't justify using the terminology I did in describing the media," Ford said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I sincerely apologize to each and every one of you.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>49</id><text>
In a statement to CNN, Reid said, "I deeply regret using such a poor choice of words.""I sincerely apologize for offending any and all Americans, especially African Americans for my improper comments."I was a proud and enthusiastic supporter of Barack Obama during the campaign and have worked as hard as I can to advance President Obama's legislative agenda," the senator from Nevada said.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
In a statement to CNN, Reid said, "I deeply regret using such a poor choice of words.</text></sentence><sentence><text>""I sincerely apologize for offending any and all Americans, especially African Americans for my improper comments.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I was a proud and enthusiastic supporter of Barack Obama during the campaign and have worked as hard as I can to advance President Obama's legislative agenda," the senator from Nevada said.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>50</id><text>
The tweet that was at the root of this chain of events has been over-interpreted. I am not ‘against' the word “cis”, or “cisgender" – I employ it myself sometimes. I do not and never have believed that being a trans woman manifests an '‘opt-in’' idea of what it is to be a woman. I invented the phrase only to discuss a hypothetical philosophical position that I was arguing against. I never applied it to trans women who typically do not experience their gender-identity as opt-in at all. I'm sorry that these points weren't clearer in what I wrote. I will be meeting with LGBT activists in Cambridge and leading trans people in the Green Party nationally soon, to listen further to their very valid concerns about some of the words I've used previously, and to seek to reach a better mutual understanding.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
The tweet that was at the root of this chain of events has been over-interpreted.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am not ‘against' the word “cis”, or “cisgender" – I employ it myself sometimes.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I do not and never have believed that being a trans woman manifests an '‘opt-in’' idea of what it is to be a woman.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I invented the phrase only to discuss a hypothetical philosophical position that I was arguing against.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I never applied it to trans women who typically do not experience their gender-identity as opt-in at all.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I'm sorry that these points weren't clearer in what I wrote.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I will be meeting with LGBT activists in Cambridge and leading trans people in the Green Party nationally soon, to listen further to their very valid concerns about some of the words I've used previously, and to seek to reach a better mutual understanding.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>51</id><text>
I’m sorry. I apologize unreservedly for the real and genuine offence and hurt caused by my tweets and my previous writing. I’m sorry, especially, for the hurt caused to transgender people, who remain sorely oppressed in our society today. Life is a journey towards understanding, and I clearly need to spend more time than I already have done listening to transgender people, and if anyone would like spare the time to share their experiences and explain what I and fellow Greens can do to help them I would be grateful for that opportunity. I am taking the LGBTIQ Greens up in their offer extended in their statement, of engaging with them to come to understand better. I am deeply sorry for the offence and hurt caused by the manner in which I have spoken about all this. I take responsibility for that. The Green Party believes unequivocally in feminism, queer rights, and trans rights, principles I believe in absolutely. Opposing the ongoing horrifying discrimination faced by trans people is absolutely vital, and I am proud to be in a party which has a long history of doing just that. I apologize for the way in which my comments have got in the way of this. I will listen to what those who have been hurt by what I’ve said are saying, and I hope to learn from the whole affair, and to improve my understanding of these matters.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I’m sorry.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize unreservedly for the real and genuine offence and hurt caused by my tweets and my previous writing.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I’m sorry, especially, for the hurt caused to transgender people, who remain sorely oppressed in our society today.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Life is a journey towards understanding, and I clearly need to spend more time than I already have done listening to transgender people, and if anyone would like spare the time to share their experiences and explain what I and fellow Greens can do to help them I would be grateful for that opportunity.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am taking the LGBTIQ Greens up in their offer extended in their statement, of engaging with them to come to understand better.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am deeply sorry for the offence and hurt caused by the manner in which I have spoken about all this.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I take responsibility for that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The Green Party believes unequivocally in feminism, queer rights, and trans rights, principles I believe in absolutely.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Opposing the ongoing horrifying discrimination faced by trans people is absolutely vital, and I am proud to be in a party which has a long history of doing just that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize for the way in which my comments have got in the way of this.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I will listen to what those who have been hurt by what I’ve said are saying, and I hope to learn from the whole affair, and to improve my understanding of these matters.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>52</id><text>
“I absolutely said, what I specifically said, is that motherhood should not play a part in the campaign,” says Leadsom. “I was pressed to say how my children had formed my views. I didn’t want it to be used as an issue. Having children has no bearing on the ability to be PM. I deeply regret that anyone has got the impression that I think otherwise.”
When I ask if she would like to apologise to Mrs May, she says: “I’ve already said to Theresa how very sorry I am for any hurt I have caused and how that article said completely the opposite of what I said and believe.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I absolutely said, what I specifically said, is that motherhood should not play a part in the campaign,” says Leadsom.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I was pressed to say how my children had formed my views.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I didn’t want it to be used as an issue.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Having children has no bearing on the ability to be PM.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I deeply regret that anyone has got the impression that I think otherwise.”
When I ask if she would like to apologise to Mrs May, she says: “I’ve already said to Theresa how very sorry I am for any hurt I have caused and how that article said completely the opposite of what I said and believe.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>53</id><text>
After the unfolding of today's events, I have decided to step down as the Liberal candidate for Calgary Nose Hill," Ala Buzreba said in a Facebook message posted around 8:30 p.m. local time.
Buzreba earlier in the day apologized after some tweets she posted as a teenager four years ago began circulating on Twitter, apparently dug up by Conservative supporters.
The 21-year-old was to run against Conservative cabinet minister Michelle Rempel. "The discussion shouldn`t be focused on me and my tweets, but rather it should be about what's best for Canadians," Buzreba said in the statement indicating she would be stepping down. "This election is about bringing real change to Ottawa and I firmly believe that Justin Trudeau and the Liberal team are best placed to do just that. "The development leaves the Liberals scrambling for a new candidate. The NDP will be nominating its candidate in the riding next week. Buzreba earlier said the comments do not reflect her current thinking. She also said she has learned a lot of lessons about social media since she posted the vitriolic comments.In one, she tells a strident defender of Israel: "Your mother should have used that coat hanger."In another, she tells a tweeter she deems a racist to "go blow your brains out you waste of sperm. "And in yet another, she reports that she just got her hair cut and looks "like a flipping lesbian.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
After the unfolding of today's events, I have decided to step down as the Liberal candidate for Calgary Nose Hill," Ala Buzreba said in a Facebook message posted around 8:30 p.m. local time.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Buzreba earlier in the day apologized after some tweets she posted as a teenager four years ago began circulating on Twitter, apparently dug up by Conservative supporters.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The 21-year-old was to run against Conservative cabinet minister Michelle Rempel.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"The discussion shouldn`t be focused on me and my tweets, but rather it should be about what's best for Canadians," Buzreba said in the statement indicating she would be stepping down.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"This election is about bringing real change to Ottawa and I firmly believe that Justin Trudeau and the Liberal team are best placed to do just that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"The development leaves the Liberals scrambling for a new candidate.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The NDP will be nominating its candidate in the riding next week.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Buzreba earlier said the comments do not reflect her current thinking.</text></sentence><sentence><text>She also said she has learned a lot of lessons about social media since she posted the vitriolic comments.In one, she tells a strident defender of Israel: "Your mother should have used that coat hanger.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"In another, she tells a tweeter she deems a racist to "go blow your brains out you waste of sperm.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"And in yet another, she reports that she just got her hair cut and looks "like a flipping lesbian.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>54</id><text>
“I want to apologize unreservedly for my past social media posts. They were insensitive and don’t reflect the person I am today,” Mr. Rinaldo wrote. “As a member of the Facebook generation I’m aware of the benefits of this forum, but should have understood the pitfalls.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I want to apologize unreservedly for my past social media posts.</text></sentence><sentence><text>They were insensitive and don’t reflect the person I am today,” Mr. Rinaldo wrote.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“As a member of the Facebook generation I’m aware of the benefits of this forum, but should have understood the pitfalls.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>55</id><text>
Mr. McKinnon was served with a legal demand notice for retraction and apology on May 24, 2006. In compliance with part of that notice, Mr. McKinnon stated on the May 25 edition of "Mike Duffy Live":
“Mike, last time we spoke -- on Tuesday -- we were discussing the latest Ipsos Reid poll. In that discussion I made statements about the methodology which were without basis in fact, and I would like to retract those statements and apologize to Ipsos Reid.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Mr. McKinnon was served with a legal demand notice for retraction and apology on May 24, 2006.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In compliance with part of that notice, Mr. McKinnon stated on the May 25 edition of "Mike Duffy Live":
“Mike, last time we spoke -- on Tuesday -- we were discussing the latest Ipsos Reid poll.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In that discussion I made statements about the methodology which were without basis in fact, and I would like to retract those statements and apologize to Ipsos Reid.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>56</id><text>
“I believe it’s important to admit mistakes when they happen. It was a mistake for a letter to go out to Scarborough-Rouge River voters saying that I would ‘scrap’ the updated curriculum,” Brown wrote in an opinion piece for the Star. “This is not my view. This is not what I will do. In fact, the opposite is true. I apologize. “I strongly support an updated curriculum that takes into account changing attitudes and the world in which children now dwell. They are being asked to understand challenging topics in ways their parents were not. “It is important to have sex education to combat homophobia, and raise important issues like consent, mental health, bullying, and gender identity. The world has changed and so should the curriculum.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I believe it’s important to admit mistakes when they happen.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was a mistake for a letter to go out to Scarborough-Rouge River voters saying that I would ‘scrap’ the updated curriculum,” Brown wrote in an opinion piece for the Star.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“This is not my view.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This is not what I will do.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In fact, the opposite is true.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I strongly support an updated curriculum that takes into account changing attitudes and the world in which children now dwell.</text></sentence><sentence><text>They are being asked to understand challenging topics in ways their parents were not.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“It is important to have sex education to combat homophobia, and raise important issues like consent, mental health, bullying, and gender identity.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The world has changed and so should the curriculum.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>57</id><text>
Kanata resident Keith Selevich said he was walking his dog Thor near the intersection of Teron Road and Beaverbrook Road around 5 p.m. Sunday when he saw someone who had been driving a white truck pull a yellow sign that read, "Have you thought of voting strategically? This is the time!" out of the ground and replace it with a Conservative sign. When the driver got out again a short distance away, Selevich said he recognized the man as Walter Pamic, the Conservative candidate the new riding of Kanata-Carleton, which has no incumbent. "I just took out the camera to record the licence plate… I kept the phone on him and found out it was him," Selevich said. Pamic said in a statement on Monday afternoon that he had come across "a number of illegal signs" along Teron Road and Beaverbrook Road. "As [the signs] violated the Canadian Elections Act, I took it upon myself to remove them," he said. "After discussing the matter with bylaw officers, I learned that I should have notified bylaw rather than remove the illegal signs myself. I apologize for this mistake.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Kanata resident Keith Selevich said he was walking his dog Thor near the intersection of Teron Road and Beaverbrook Road around 5 p.m. Sunday when he saw someone who had been driving a white truck pull a yellow sign that read, "Have you thought of voting strategically?</text></sentence><sentence><text>This is the time!</text></sentence><sentence><text>" out of the ground and replace it with a Conservative sign.</text></sentence><sentence><text>When the driver got out again a short distance away, Selevich said he recognized the man as Walter Pamic, the Conservative candidate the new riding of Kanata-Carleton, which has no incumbent.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I just took out the camera to record the licence plate… I kept the phone on him and found out it was him," Selevich said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Pamic said in a statement on Monday afternoon that he had come across "a number of illegal signs" along Teron Road and Beaverbrook Road.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"As [the signs] violated the Canadian Elections Act, I took it upon myself to remove them," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"After discussing the matter with bylaw officers, I learned that I should have notified bylaw rather than remove the illegal signs myself.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize for this mistake.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>58</id><text>
I regret the comments that I’ve made, as many as ten years ago and for these I apologize.
During this time, as a gay teenager and someone who was struggling, I felt an overwhelming pressure and made incorrect statements to mask the confusion I was feeling. I did this in order to present an image of myself that I felt was expected of a straight man.
Since that time I have been active in the LGBT community and have worked to serve the people in our community as best as I can. I have served on the board of directors for a respected organization, OutSport Toronto, known for promoting the participation of sport activities within the LGBT community, in addition to advocacy against LGBT discrimination in sport. I have also been a long-time supporter of LGBT charities, AIDS service charities and community athletics.
I’m grateful to offer my support 10 years later, toward some of the support structures that are so necessary to help LGBT youth who were in the same position that I was in. My hope is that they don’t feel alone or afraid, and that they can access organizations that are here to support them.
I look forward to continue working to serve my community and I commit to representing their best interests if elected as the Member of Parliament for Toronto Centre.
I will not comment further on these decade old posts. My priority today is focused on promoting Stephen Harper’s plan to create jobs, cut taxes and keep our communities safe.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I regret the comments that I’ve made, as many as ten years ago and for these I apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>During this time, as a gay teenager and someone who was struggling, I felt an overwhelming pressure and made incorrect statements to mask the confusion I was feeling.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I did this in order to present an image of myself that I felt was expected of a straight man.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Since that time I have been active in the LGBT community and have worked to serve the people in our community as best as I can.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have served on the board of directors for a respected organization, OutSport Toronto, known for promoting the participation of sport activities within the LGBT community, in addition to advocacy against LGBT discrimination in sport.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have also been a long-time supporter of LGBT charities, AIDS service charities and community athletics.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I’m grateful to offer my support 10 years later, toward some of the support structures that are so necessary to help LGBT youth who were in the same position that I was in.</text></sentence><sentence><text>My hope is that they don’t feel alone or afraid, and that they can access organizations that are here to support them.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I look forward to continue working to serve my community and I commit to representing their best interests if elected as the Member of Parliament for Toronto Centre.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I will not comment further on these decade old posts.</text></sentence><sentence><text>My priority today is focused on promoting Stephen Harper’s plan to create jobs, cut taxes and keep our communities safe.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>59</id><text>
Lien apologized later Monday afternoon, recognizing he "made a dumb comment.
I apologize to Sarah Hoffman (sic) and all who read it for my insensitive remark. Once again, I'm sorry.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Lien apologized later Monday afternoon, recognizing he "made a dumb comment.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize to Sarah Hoffman (sic) and all who read it for my insensitive remark.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Once again, I'm sorry.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>60</id><text>
“Last weekend I shared a post on social media that was inappropriate in nature. Recognizing that it was in poor taste I quickly removed it,” Fox said. “It wasn't my intention to give offense to anyone or to objectify anyone by sharing the post. It was a mistake on my part. I regret doing it and I sincerely apologize to anyone that I may have offended with my action.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“Last weekend I shared a post on social media that was inappropriate in nature.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Recognizing that it was in poor taste I quickly removed it,” Fox said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“It wasn't my intention to give offense to anyone or to objectify anyone by sharing the post.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was a mistake on my part.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I regret doing it and I sincerely apologize to anyone that I may have offended with my action.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>61</id><text>
As the Executive Director of the North Carolina Republican Party, we offer our sincere and unqualified apology for the mistake made on Twitter last night regarding Gov. Kaine’s lapel pin. The tweet was wrong on the facts, wrong in tone and should not have happened. We would like to offer a sincere apology to Senator Tim Kaine, his family, and his Marine son who is honorably serving overseas. The members of the staff that were invoked are facing severe internal sanctions and mandatory retraining. When we learned of our mistake, we immediately took steps to rectify it. There are now procedural measures in place to make sure it does not happen again. While I did not see or authorize the tweet, as the Director of our organization I take full responsibility for our carelessness. Again, we are incredibly thankful for the service of Sen. Kaine’s son, and all United States military, past and present, who fight for our freedom. We demand accountability from our elected officials and our government. Those standards apply do and should apply to us as well.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
As the Executive Director of the North Carolina Republican Party, we offer our sincere and unqualified apology for the mistake made on Twitter last night regarding Gov.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Kaine’s lapel pin.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The tweet was wrong on the facts, wrong in tone and should not have happened.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We would like to offer a sincere apology to Senator Tim Kaine, his family, and his Marine son who is honorably serving overseas.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The members of the staff that were invoked are facing severe internal sanctions and mandatory retraining.</text></sentence><sentence><text>When we learned of our mistake, we immediately took steps to rectify it.</text></sentence><sentence><text>There are now procedural measures in place to make sure it does not happen again.</text></sentence><sentence><text>While I did not see or authorize the tweet, as the Director of our organization I take full responsibility for our carelessness.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Again, we are incredibly thankful for the service of Sen. Kaine’s son, and all United States military, past and present, who fight for our freedom.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We demand accountability from our elected officials and our government.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Those standards apply do and should apply to us as well.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>62</id><text>
“The Holodomor was an atrocious and intentional act that saw the deaths of millions upon millions of Ukrainians,” reads the apology released by the Wildrose party on Friday. “Any interpretation of the column collaborated on by the nine Wildrose MLAs as dismissing the Holodomor as a horrendous act was completely unintentional, and we unreservedly apologize. “Out of an abundance of caution and respect for Ukrainian Albertans, the post was removed and a revised version has been posted.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“The Holodomor was an atrocious and intentional act that saw the deaths of millions upon millions of Ukrainians,” reads the apology released by the Wildrose party on Friday.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“Any interpretation of the column collaborated on by the nine Wildrose MLAs as dismissing the Holodomor as a horrendous act was completely unintentional, and we unreservedly apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“Out of an abundance of caution and respect for Ukrainian Albertans, the post was removed and a revised version has been posted.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>63</id><text>
James acknowledges his CNN appearance wasn't his proudest moment. "It is salacious. It does not lift up Utah and I do apologize I said that, but I was just explaining how it is that....I just...My level of frustration and I went there." Evans still stands by his claim. He says the reason he brought up the allegation is because no one else is. the Utah Republican Party Chairman says he's frustrated over his perceived doubled standard over how the media treats allegations against trump and those against Hillary Clinton. "I will say this time and time again that we must all stand up against any kind of assault or violence against women, children or anyone, but when you're three weeks out from an election and people bring forth allegations I think there's a sensitivity that the media should approach these on both sides.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
James acknowledges his CNN appearance wasn't his proudest moment.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"It is salacious.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It does not lift up Utah and I do apologize I said that, but I was just explaining how it is that....I just...My level of frustration and I went there.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" Evans still stands by his claim.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He says the reason he brought up the allegation is because no one else is.</text></sentence><sentence><text>the Utah Republican Party Chairman says he's frustrated over his perceived doubled standard over how the media treats allegations against trump and those against Hillary Clinton.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I will say this time and time again that we must all stand up against any kind of assault or violence against women, children or anyone, but when you're three weeks out from an election and people bring forth allegations I think there's a sensitivity that the media should approach these on both sides.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>64</id><text>
With a big weekend coming upon us, poor wording was used. His request should not have been called divisive and we apologize for that. We have reached out to invite him to meet with the Chair (Susan Swecker) for a one-on-one meeting to determine how we can move forward together," the apology reads, in part.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
With a big weekend coming upon us, poor wording was used.</text></sentence><sentence><text>His request should not have been called divisive and we apologize for that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We have reached out to invite him to meet with the Chair (Susan Swecker) for a one-on-one meeting to determine how we can move forward together," the apology reads, in part.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>65</id><text>
Today she apologized, “I was trying and obviously failing badly at delivering something a bit edgy and…I should have realized that having traveled so much in the previous 48 hours that I was probably too sleep deprived to pull it off properly so I do apologize.  Again it wasn’t my intention to offend anybody”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Today she apologized, “I was trying and obviously failing badly at delivering something a bit edgy and…I should have realized that having traveled so much in the previous 48 hours that I was probably too sleep deprived to pull it off properly so I do apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Again it wasn’t my intention to offend anybody”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>66</id><text>
Leech offered an apology for his remarks Tuesday. He said he had made them on the spur of the moment and hadn't put his point across very well. "I apologize if something was said at the moment ... that misrepresented the community or myself," Leech said at a campaign stop in Calgary. "What I was trying to say, which didn’t come out that way and I apologize ... is that it’s not a disadvantage for me to be Caucasian to represent the diverse cultures of my riding.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Leech offered an apology for his remarks Tuesday.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He said he had made them on the spur of the moment and hadn't put his point across very well.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I apologize if something was said at the moment ... that misrepresented the community or myself," Leech said at a campaign stop in Calgary.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"What I was trying to say, which didn’t come out that way and I apologize ... is that it’s not a disadvantage for me to be Caucasian to represent the diverse cultures of my riding.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>67</id><text>
“It has been just over a month since I and a majority of my Wildrose colleagues made the decision to start a process to unify conservatives under the leadership of Premier Jim Prentice,” she wrote.
“It has not gone as expected. It has not been an easy path. It has angered a lot of people.
“For that I am truly sorry.”
Smith said after six years of trying to build a “fiscally conservative and socially mainstream party,” she failed and feared the Wildrose was in danger of becoming an “NDP of the right.” Although she apologized for not talking about her decision to change parties with her constituents, Smith said she believes voters will come around. “I truly believe that Albertans will see – as I do – that Premier Prentice is the right choice to lead Alberta, especially through the coming years of tough economic times,” she said. “As hard as the last month has been for me personally, the more I see this premier in action, the more I can say with confidence that we have seen a return to honest, capable and ethical government. “I am so very proud to serve under his leadership.” Smith added after discussing her future with her husband she has decided to seek the PC nomination in her Highwood riding in the next election. “I would be honored to continue to serve my community as their elected MLA and I am pleased to confirm that I will be seeking the PC nomination in the Highwood constituency,” she said.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“It has been just over a month since I and a majority of my Wildrose colleagues made the decision to start a process to unify conservatives under the leadership of Premier Jim Prentice,” she wrote.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“It has not gone as expected.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It has not been an easy path.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It has angered a lot of people.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“For that I am truly sorry.”
Smith said after six years of trying to build a “fiscally conservative and socially mainstream party,” she failed and feared the Wildrose was in danger of becoming an “NDP of the right.” Although she apologized for not talking about her decision to change parties with her constituents, Smith said she believes voters will come around.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I truly believe that Albertans will see – as I do – that Premier Prentice is the right choice to lead Alberta, especially through the coming years of tough economic times,” she said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“As hard as the last month has been for me personally, the more I see this premier in action, the more I can say with confidence that we have seen a return to honest, capable and ethical government.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I am so very proud to serve under his leadership.” Smith added after discussing her future with her husband she has decided to seek the PC nomination in her Highwood riding in the next election.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I would be honored to continue to serve my community as their elected MLA and I am pleased to confirm that I will be seeking the PC nomination in the Highwood constituency,” she said.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>68</id><text>
“My failure to strongly recommend a similar process to the Wildrose caucus was a mistake on my part. It was a disservice to those who sought my counsel and to those who have placed their trust in my commitment to democracy — a mistake for which I now sincerely apologize to all concerned.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“My failure to strongly recommend a similar process to the Wildrose caucus was a mistake on my part.</text></sentence><sentence><text>It was a disservice to those who sought my counsel and to those who have placed their trust in my commitment to democracy — a mistake for which I now sincerely apologize to all concerned.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>69</id><text>
On Friday he made good on that promise in the Red Room at the Nova Scotia legislature before a crowd that included former residents, their families and supporters. “It is one of the great tragedies in our province’s history that your cries for help were greeted with silence for so long. Some of you have said you felt invisible. You are invisible no longer. We hear your voices and we grieve for your pain. We are sorry.” Smith, who accepted the apology on behalf of former residents and the group VOICES, which formed during the quest for justice, said he’s glad things are no longer confrontational with the government. Former residents no longer feel like they have to fight to be believed, he said.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
On Friday he made good on that promise in the Red Room at the Nova Scotia legislature before a crowd that included former residents, their families and supporters.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“It is one of the great tragedies in our province’s history that your cries for help were greeted with silence for so long.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Some of you have said you felt invisible.</text></sentence><sentence><text>You are invisible no longer.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We hear your voices and we grieve for your pain.</text></sentence><sentence><text>We are sorry.” Smith, who accepted the apology on behalf of former residents and the group VOICES, which formed during the quest for justice, said he’s glad things are no longer confrontational with the government.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Former residents no longer feel like they have to fight to be believed, he said.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>70</id><text>
Over the last few days, I have used some intemperate language that I regret," Martin, a longtime MP who is seeking re-election in Winnipeg-Centre, wrote in a statement on the weekend.
I would like to offer an unreserved apology to my fellow candidates and to anyone else who may have taken offence to the tone and content of these remarks. I hope we can move past this and return to having a healthy discussion of the issues affecting Winnipeg-Centre voters.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Over the last few days, I have used some intemperate language that I regret," Martin, a longtime MP who is seeking re-election in Winnipeg-Centre, wrote in a statement on the weekend.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I would like to offer an unreserved apology to my fellow candidates and to anyone else who may have taken offence to the tone and content of these remarks.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I hope we can move past this and return to having a healthy discussion of the issues affecting Winnipeg-Centre voters.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>71</id><text>
Alex Johnstone conceded she should not have made her remarks. "Attention was recently drawn to a comment I posted on social media seven years ago," Johnstone said. "While never intending any malice, this comment was clearly inappropriate. I would like to offer my unreserved apology.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Alex Johnstone conceded she should not have made her remarks.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"Attention was recently drawn to a comment I posted on social media seven years ago," Johnstone said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"While never intending any malice, this comment was clearly inappropriate.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I would like to offer my unreserved apology.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>72</id><text>
I sincerely apologize for the offensive comments I made on social media in the past. These comments were inappropriate and do not reflect the level of professionalism exemplified by those running for office. This is not an excuse, but let me put those comments in context. In 2009, I lost my partner in a car accident in which a drunk driver was involved. This was an extremely difficult time for me personally and something I do not wish upon anyone. This emotional anguish led to an alcohol dependency problem and a complete lack of judgement when posting on social media. I am not proud of this period in my life, but with the help of my family and friends, I am proud to say that this is now behind me. I have moved forward in my life, and I am now dedicated to giving back to my community and serving the residents of Peace River–Westlock. Again, I apologize for these offensive comments and I reiterate that they do not reflect who I am today.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I sincerely apologize for the offensive comments I made on social media in the past.</text></sentence><sentence><text>These comments were inappropriate and do not reflect the level of professionalism exemplified by those running for office.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This is not an excuse, but let me put those comments in context.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In 2009, I lost my partner in a car accident in which a drunk driver was involved.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This was an extremely difficult time for me personally and something I do not wish upon anyone.</text></sentence><sentence><text>This emotional anguish led to an alcohol dependency problem and a complete lack of judgement when posting on social media.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I am not proud of this period in my life, but with the help of my family and friends, I am proud to say that this is now behind me.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I have moved forward in my life, and I am now dedicated to giving back to my community and serving the residents of Peace River–Westlock.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Again, I apologize for these offensive comments and I reiterate that they do not reflect who I am today.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>73</id><text>
When looking back at them, I understand that they are offensive and have no place in our political discourse. I want to apologize particularly to the Jewish and Muslim communities for these insensitive statements," she wrote. "Anyone who knows me, knows that I have utmost respect for all religions and communities and those past comments do not truly reflect who I am." She said she understood that her past comments had become a distraction to the Liberals campaign and would "immediately cease" her own campaign, close her office and end all her political activities.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
When looking back at them, I understand that they are offensive and have no place in our political discourse.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I want to apologize particularly to the Jewish and Muslim communities for these insensitive statements," she wrote.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"Anyone who knows me, knows that I have utmost respect for all religions and communities and those past comments do not truly reflect who I am.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" She said she understood that her past comments had become a distraction to the Liberals campaign and would "immediately cease" her own campaign, close her office and end all her political activities.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>74</id><text>
Mr. Strickland apologized in a statement to the Washington Examiner Wednesday morning. “That was an insensitive remark and I apologize,” he said.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Mr. Strickland apologized in a statement to the Washington Examiner Wednesday morning.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“That was an insensitive remark and I apologize,” he said.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>75</id><text>
I do not hold these views and apologize unreservedly for making these comments in 2005," Singh Kahlon said in a statement. "I want to reaffirm my commitment to protecting human rights for all people in all circumstances without exception.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I do not hold these views and apologize unreservedly for making these comments in 2005," Singh Kahlon said in a statement.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I want to reaffirm my commitment to protecting human rights for all people in all circumstances without exception.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>76</id><text>
Myers told CBC News Friday that he made the remark in the heat of the moment after a long campaign and it wasn't what he meant to say. "I certainly think that the people of Prince Edward Island probably deserve my apology and I apologize to them if they in any way are offended by my use of those words. I think I'll talk to the Premier on a private basis down the road and we'll get past it.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Myers told CBC News Friday that he made the remark in the heat of the moment after a long campaign and it wasn't what he meant to say.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I certainly think that the people of Prince Edward Island probably deserve my apology and I apologize to them if they in any way are offended by my use of those words.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I think I'll talk to the Premier on a private basis down the road and we'll get past it.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>77</id><text>
On Monday, a very apologetic Murphy stood up after question period and issued a formal apology to the House.
Since being elected as the Member of Parliament for Charlottetown about seven years ago, I have attempted to conduct myself with dignity and honour," he said. "That certainly was not the case last Thursday afternoon. I deeply regret my actions.
He also apologized to Mulroney and his family for any embarrassment they might have caused.
Although the remarks were rhetorical and meant solely as hyperbole, they were highly improper and ought not to have been made.
In an interview with The Guardian immediately after reading his apology in the House, Murphy said he hopes to put the affair behind him.
I really don't have anything to say other than what I said in the House. I'd prefer just to leave it at that. I made the apology, it was accepted by the House, and the House considers the matter over and so do I.
He said he hasn't received any negative feedback from his constituents, and hopes the whole thing is at an end.
You do something that you shouldn't have done, you apologize and you retract your remarks and that's it," he said. "And I don't want to go on and make excuses. I think the apology speaks for itself.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
On Monday, a very apologetic Murphy stood up after question period and issued a formal apology to the House.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Since being elected as the Member of Parliament for Charlottetown about seven years ago, I have attempted to conduct myself with dignity and honour," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"That certainly was not the case last Thursday afternoon.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I deeply regret my actions.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He also apologized to Mulroney and his family for any embarrassment they might have caused.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Although the remarks were rhetorical and meant solely as hyperbole, they were highly improper and ought not to have been made.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In an interview with The Guardian immediately after reading his apology in the House, Murphy said he hopes to put the affair behind him.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I really don't have anything to say other than what I said in the House.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I'd prefer just to leave it at that.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I made the apology, it was accepted by the House, and the House considers the matter over and so do I.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He said he hasn't received any negative feedback from his constituents, and hopes the whole thing is at an end.</text></sentence><sentence><text>You do something that you shouldn't have done, you apologize and you retract your remarks and that's it," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"And I don't want to go on and make excuses.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I think the apology speaks for itself.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>78</id><text>
Mr. Picotte issued a statement Monday apologizing for the remarks.  "I have, in the context of an emotional speech where I evoked the future of our children, made comments that could appear offensive and that do not reflect my thinking," Mr. Picotte said. "If my comments hurt Mr. Boisclair or any other person, I want to say that I am sincerely sorry and in this regard, I offer my most profound apologies.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Mr. Picotte issued a statement Monday apologizing for the remarks.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I have, in the context of an emotional speech where I evoked the future of our children, made comments that could appear offensive and that do not reflect my thinking," Mr. Picotte said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"If my comments hurt Mr. Boisclair or any other person, I want to say that I am sincerely sorry and in this regard, I offer my most profound apologies.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>79</id><text>
Poilievre, the parliamentary secretary to the president of the Treasury Board, rose in the House of Commons on Thursday afternoon to acknowledge his mistake.
Yesterday on a day when the House and all Canadians were celebrating a new beginning, I made remarks that were hurtful and wrong," he said. "I accept responsibility for them and I apologize.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Poilievre, the parliamentary secretary to the president of the Treasury Board, rose in the House of Commons on Thursday afternoon to acknowledge his mistake.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Yesterday on a day when the House and all Canadians were celebrating a new beginning, I made remarks that were hurtful and wrong," he said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I accept responsibility for them and I apologize.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>80</id><text>
If my comments offended anyone I sincerely apologize," Barrette said. "I had no intention — not today or before — to make any link between those events and my comments or any political party whatsoever.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
If my comments offended anyone I sincerely apologize," Barrette said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"I had no intention — not today or before — to make any link between those events and my comments or any political party whatsoever.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>81</id><text>
I apologise for that thoughtless gesture during PM's tribute to Mr Harper - a joke in poor taste that I regret very much.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I apologise for that thoughtless gesture during PM's tribute to Mr Harper - a joke in poor taste that I regret very much.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>82</id><text>
“It was an error of judgment, very early coming into politics, and I’m sorry if I offended anyone from doing that, but please can I move on?
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“It was an error of judgment, very early coming into politics, and I’m sorry if I offended anyone from doing that, but please can I move on?
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>83</id><text>
“To those NBA players and others who are unfairly categorized by my comments, please accept my apologies,” Garofalo wrote on Twitter.
“In the last 24 hours, I’ve had the opportunity to re-learn one of life’s lessons: whenever any of us are offering opinions, it is best to refer to people as individuals as opposed to groups. Last night, I publicly commented on the NBA and I sincerely apologize to those who I unfairly categorized. The NBA has many examples of players and owners who are role models for our communities and for our country. Those individuals did not deserve that criticism and I apologize. In addition, it’s been brought to my attention that I was mistaken and the NBA policy on drug enforcement is stronger than I previously believed. Again, I offer my sincere apologies for my comments.”
Garofalo is up for reelection this year.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“To those NBA players and others who are unfairly categorized by my comments, please accept my apologies,” Garofalo wrote on Twitter.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“In the last 24 hours, I’ve had the opportunity to re-learn one of life’s lessons: whenever any of us are offering opinions, it is best to refer to people as individuals as opposed to groups.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Last night, I publicly commented on the NBA and I sincerely apologize to those who I unfairly categorized.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The NBA has many examples of players and owners who are role models for our communities and for our country.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Those individuals did not deserve that criticism and I apologize.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In addition, it’s been brought to my attention that I was mistaken and the NBA policy on drug enforcement is stronger than I previously believed.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Again, I offer my sincere apologies for my comments.”
Garofalo is up for reelection this year.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>84</id><text>
The congressman later issued an apology for his initial statement a few hours after the interview aired. "What is taking place in my hometown right now breaks my heart," Pittenger wrote. "My intent was to discuss the lack of economic mobility for African Americans because of failed policies. I apologize to those I offended and hope that we can bring peace and calm to Charlotte.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
The congressman later issued an apology for his initial statement a few hours after the interview aired.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"What is taking place in my hometown right now breaks my heart," Pittenger wrote.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"My intent was to discuss the lack of economic mobility for African Americans because of failed policies.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize to those I offended and hope that we can bring peace and calm to Charlotte.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>85</id><text>
“I believe you deserve the truth from me directly. Last summer I was old enough to know better, but I guess I was still young enough to do something stupid. I chose to send improper texts to a young man. I won’t go into details out of respect for the rights and privacy of all parties. I made a bad decision. I regret my actions. I apologize to the families involved and anyone who I embarrassed. Especially my own family and the people of Jefferson. Now I will work every day to prove that good people can rise from a bad decision. I want to reassure the citizens of Jefferson that I never abused or misused my powers as a public official. And I’m certainly not afraid of the future, because I’m smart enough to never repeat the past.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
“I believe you deserve the truth from me directly.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Last summer I was old enough to know better, but I guess I was still young enough to do something stupid.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I chose to send improper texts to a young man.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I won’t go into details out of respect for the rights and privacy of all parties.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I made a bad decision.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I regret my actions.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize to the families involved and anyone who I embarrassed.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Especially my own family and the people of Jefferson.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Now I will work every day to prove that good people can rise from a bad decision.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I want to reassure the citizens of Jefferson that I never abused or misused my powers as a public official.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And I’m certainly not afraid of the future, because I’m smart enough to never repeat the past.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>86</id><text>
Monday night’s Twin Falls City Council meeting began with a public apology from council member Greg Lanting after a Facebook comment he made over the weekend regarding the Fawnbrook case made internet headlines. Lanting says that he did not delete the post but that maybe the original poster did. He said he would like to make amends to the family in whatever capacity he could. “I was wrong, I would like to apologize and I went on to try to make amends and if somebody could tell me, I could no longer find the liberty of justice Go Fund Me account,” said council member Greg Lanting. “I’d like to make an additional contribution.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Monday night’s Twin Falls City Council meeting began with a public apology from council member Greg Lanting after a Facebook comment he made over the weekend regarding the Fawnbrook case made internet headlines.</text></sentence><sentence><text>Lanting says that he did not delete the post but that maybe the original poster did.</text></sentence><sentence><text>He said he would like to make amends to the family in whatever capacity he could.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I was wrong, I would like to apologize and I went on to try to make amends and if somebody could tell me, I could no longer find the liberty of justice Go Fund Me account,” said council member Greg Lanting.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“I’d like to make an additional contribution.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>87</id><text>
In his apology tweets, Farenthold said “I was thrown off by the anchor’s use of a hypothetical question”, adding: “I apologize for my failure to immediately condemn anyone who would say something as outrageous as they like raping women.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
In his apology tweets, Farenthold said “I was thrown off by the anchor’s use of a hypothetical question”, adding: “I apologize for my failure to immediately condemn anyone who would say something as outrageous as they like raping women.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>88</id><text>
I'm happy now to say in person, in front of all of you, that I apologized for what took place. There was the use of a car service in the conducting of my ministerial duties and the costs were too high," Philpott said. "Those costs were inappropriate. I apologize for that.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
I'm happy now to say in person, in front of all of you, that I apologized for what took place.</text></sentence><sentence><text>There was the use of a car service in the conducting of my ministerial duties and the costs were too high," Philpott said.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"Those costs were inappropriate.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I apologize for that.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>89</id><text>
Perry, who hadn't returned calls since Monday, sent an email to The Sun shortly after 5 p.m. Wednesday, explaining his role in the altercation. The email said he would be available to speak to the media Thursday. “Anyone who knows me, knows that it takes quite a bit to rile me up. What began as a silly disagreement over a legal campaign yard sign — that was authorized by the owner to be placed in his yard — escalated, and for my part in that, I apologize," the email read.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Perry, who hadn't returned calls since Monday, sent an email to The Sun shortly after 5 p.m. Wednesday, explaining his role in the altercation.</text></sentence><sentence><text>The email said he would be available to speak to the media Thursday.</text></sentence><sentence><text>“Anyone who knows me, knows that it takes quite a bit to rile me up.</text></sentence><sentence><text>What began as a silly disagreement over a legal campaign yard sign — that was authorized by the owner to be placed in his yard — escalated, and for my part in that, I apologize," the email read.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>90</id><text>
Spencer Cox (R-Utah) is the state’s Lieutenant Governor and a party leader. In a speech at a vigil held for the victims of the shooting at the Pulse nightclub in Orlando, Florida, Cox apologized for his past treatment of LGBT individuals: “There were some kids in my class that were different than me, and sometimes I wasn’t kind to them. I didn’t know it at the time, but I know now that they were gay. I regret not treating them with the kindness, dignity and respect — the love — that they deserved. For that, I sincerely and humbly apologize.” He went on to praise the LGBT community for their patience and openness in spite of past treatment: “You have treated me with the kindness, dignity, and respect — the love — that I very often did not deserve. And it has made me love you.”
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Spencer Cox (R-Utah) is the state’s Lieutenant Governor and a party leader.</text></sentence><sentence><text>In a speech at a vigil held for the victims of the shooting at the Pulse nightclub in Orlando, Florida, Cox apologized for his past treatment of LGBT individuals: “There were some kids in my class that were different than me, and sometimes I wasn’t kind to them.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I didn’t know it at the time, but I know now that they were gay.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I regret not treating them with the kindness, dignity and respect — the love — that they deserved.</text></sentence><sentence><text>For that, I sincerely and humbly apologize.” He went on to praise the LGBT community for their patience and openness in spite of past treatment: “You have treated me with the kindness, dignity, and respect — the love — that I very often did not deserve.</text></sentence><sentence><text>And it has made me love you.”
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>91</id><text>
McAllister, who ran on a platform of family values, asked for forgiveness Monday night after the newspaper posted the video on its website. "There's no doubt I've fallen short and I'm asking for forgiveness. I'm asking for forgiveness from God, my wife, my kids, my staff and my constituents who elected me to serve," McAllister said in his apology.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
McAllister, who ran on a platform of family values, asked for forgiveness Monday night after the newspaper posted the video on its website.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"There's no doubt I've fallen short and I'm asking for forgiveness.</text></sentence><sentence><text>I'm asking for forgiveness from God, my wife, my kids, my staff and my constituents who elected me to serve," McAllister said in his apology.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse><excuse><id>92</id><text>
Twenty-eight years ago, I had a two-year romantic relationship with a fellow college student that ended with inexcusable behavior on my part," Wu said in the statement, which was posted on his campaign Web site early Tuesday morning. "As a 21-year-old, I hurt someone I cared very much about." "I take full responsibility for my actions and I am very sorry." He did not elaborate, but he said, "This single event forever changed my life and the person that I have become.
</text><sentences><sentence><text>
Twenty-eight years ago, I had a two-year romantic relationship with a fellow college student that ended with inexcusable behavior on my part," Wu said in the statement, which was posted on his campaign Web site early Tuesday morning.</text></sentence><sentence><text>"As a 21-year-old, I hurt someone I cared very much about.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" "I take full responsibility for my actions and I am very sorry.</text></sentence><sentence><text>" He did not elaborate, but he said, "This single event forever changed my life and the person that I have become.
</text></sentence></sentences></excuse></excuses>