<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<excuses>
    <excuse>
<name>excuse name 1</name>
<date>03/31/04</date>
<author>author name 3a756e9f-b6fb-419a-aff0-f73f2758ea45</author>
<city>city name f3bab08b-8c0b-49d3-9b6e-9f9c1feec6cc</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>a woke from troubled dreams, he found himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text> the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text> - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be hea</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f4473574-c246-4ba8-a2ac-a2cd863a7370</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 8ab44e7e-3e82-489b-9c28-b58819fc8415</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 2</name>
<date>11/23/96</date>
<author>author name 7bf4819d-5d2c-4c34-bcb5-d94faa4c755a</author>
<city>city name 40aeac94-9af3-4528-b8ac-48eba14dc8a8</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ttle bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as so</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text> to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text> Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards th</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f4c5bc8f-ad20-4883-a65e-0ad05a706c6d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography dea189af-6545-4530-b08b-2c28adcb46af</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 3</name>
<date>03/28/97</date>
<author>author name 4d5d8ded-3cfe-482b-9da1-86f50a8a3888</author>
<city>city name 2c16e860-75f6-46bb-bf59-a69ce1d0e6c1</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>e, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>p to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>e the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 05bd8bfe-17fa-4349-9a76-2419f17b8911</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 43725b16-1432-4a1a-9665-6d6b057e8fc6</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 4</name>
<date>07/08/06</date>
<author>author name 04ce8c6e-fc98-41bc-be12-d3229644df1b</author>
<city>city name 56df2cf5-9e68-41d2-9fc1-6fa75e0f5b9c</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to co</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>e was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get e</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 72f17e01-1be9-4ce7-92ba-b68f9c781888</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography cdb04c07-674f-4644-a794-351793ff0d3a</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 5</name>
<date>10/16/15</date>
<author>author name afa37921-7460-4bb3-8fd3-8a7e55618c2c</author>
<city>city name 88ae1409-fb71-4619-9b43-795d256d32ed</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>as overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning t</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 44b2618e-2cd7-428d-a56d-a7bddb2eabf9</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 49936ef3-b758-4f3f-b651-99816a7377d4</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 6</name>
<date>01/29/97</date>
<author>author name 8541add0-3159-4aab-a7d7-e30278b09a6b</author>
<city>city name 50150b9e-c2e7-4e48-9c77-708f93fe885c</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hea</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when y</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 7afb770b-de64-4406-a292-8595dc01135c</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 234a2116-c4e2-4051-839c-d1c67fff4b79</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 7</name>
<date>09/03/16</date>
<author>author name 06bb2e5c-20a0-4a81-9ec4-036259757252</author>
<city>city name 5048907e-1103-4e6b-abf2-0ea9e6974532</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money tog</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>t to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his de</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 9973f205-3e16-4556-9614-762e2665ab8d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography a7411eba-9b39-45a8-8a28-0ff518b7c19f</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 8</name>
<date>08/24/99</date>
<author>author name 0b4e10d2-2232-4ca7-a148-bd5c13b7bc00</author>
<city>city name 7676495b-06c3-45c8-b65a-821d5202e3b1</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>y what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the do</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>n went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock trai</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 0b5699c1-b122-4fa1-bdd3-2d0e3a036758</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 8940cbb6-1a88-4633-910a-260bc8b493cd</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 9</name>
<date>09/18/02</date>
<author>author name 88379572-9df5-447b-ba0a-055f1e5b045b</author>
<city>city name 9e555258-0af0-4094-b6d3-726eda7d9333</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my n</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>e of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source bcaac88d-d69b-4549-8f4d-c85dca5e4fa0</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 375b6e43-3e09-4e70-a402-a9627b1a5956</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 10</name>
<date>03/12/05</date>
<author>author name 4c4cd8be-8d0e-4031-a59b-c1631e1509f4</author>
<city>city name 5a67124a-951e-4f2b-a03b-ce01fffc5799</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>as something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with differ</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>f onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering le</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>ping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He mu</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 300384de-159a-4227-87d8-31e8629243d5</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography adfe77a1-3c3f-4794-b5df-9dd506df6eb7</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 11</name>
<date>12/13/08</date>
<author>author name 99082c74-e11b-41f6-bb53-a50255897ba9</author>
<city>city name 2fb820d5-85a6-4c1c-9162-d4e6d6c8dfc6</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train g</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>ecause of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>t. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assist</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text> past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probabl</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source b23d890e-2c9f-401a-b0d9-a51c49e90d42</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 684cf264-5520-44c0-aa6f-dc5b99636346</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 12</name>
<date>09/23/99</date>
<author>author name 1c139fd5-5352-4d14-ade1-3dfc42cd0534</author>
<city>city name 9ea85425-27c8-4f74-89b5-8d06ecdb1737</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>ed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text> pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could s</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 4cb1821d-3075-4c76-87d9-53c485c4d8c1</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 0ad25ecd-4ff8-4003-9fd2-778021ab31b1</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 13</name>
<date>10/17/10</date>
<author>author name 3a58aa01-946a-4cdc-90ce-568d09dd3eb4</author>
<city>city name e562262f-bb4a-419e-bd11-3f34458d6b80</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>hough, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommend</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doc</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 9a9f709f-9a1b-4eb2-aae7-24f44dd6667c</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 5643c305-3259-454c-9ccd-b124fbb81020</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 14</name>
<date>03/24/04</date>
<author>author name 9da58aba-5c72-45b5-aae4-22e8c6ae204b</author>
<city>city name a48f86a2-07e1-4cf3-b270-da6dc94b2faa</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because th</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>ime", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are a</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk!</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 6f5db18f-18a0-4481-953d-cfe3b3036ed9</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 2529ab64-29d1-4390-8059-7951b9152155</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 15</name>
<date>04/20/07</date>
<author>author name f67976eb-3a37-4ed0-9075-586374fc5a9e</author>
<city>city name 80402abb-3e7d-42f9-ad8c-e64347a468ae</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>d the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at t</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text> feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 870baad4-8740-42d1-a508-fced59b0a262</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 0149d224-efc9-4c95-94ab-2fd8d1d4529d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 16</name>
<date>03/02/99</date>
<author>author name bd071f8f-dd89-48f3-9781-8ae54d567caa</author>
<city>city name 6a755ada-3345-4add-bc85-c8110eaddf0f</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rol</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>s lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and hous</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ould be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a l</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 4ce4ac98-6af9-4e27-bd10-e84b7a859b7e</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 62afe0a9-7399-461b-b58e-9c3197413ad8</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 17</name>
<date>01/15/11</date>
<author>author name bd98f347-85f6-46d5-b241-78b710615669</author>
<city>city name 8bc88b86-e21b-40cb-811d-7a8f55bab48d</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>mself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>ught, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to wher</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 63b35c15-170f-4d24-b3be-057fa188d938</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 5ad025f7-b6f6-46c8-85f4-15b3e51e9ac6</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 18</name>
<date>09/16/07</date>
<author>author name d4b7a1bf-2c2a-4ef5-8394-c488ab722060</author>
<city>city name 5ab9ca29-b77a-46d0-9e6d-c8f8c8d0487d</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>as, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>o, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money t</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 7f65ee1c-355c-47cb-a163-24eea4c11fe1</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 752ccf2f-e7dc-4b0c-80b2-172d7c2b0844</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 19</name>
<date>11/28/04</date>
<author>author name 4be042d1-12ac-483e-8fa6-fe137a253263</author>
<city>city name 15a17e3f-5cec-4532-a6bf-22b0cf0241e2</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>e to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 513a133f-d83f-4204-a6ae-dd685be56564</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 288b481c-96dd-48e4-861e-fa47fa829085</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 20</name>
<date>01/21/10</date>
<author>author name 4ecd5f07-6667-40fd-a4a8-6c3fa3cff686</author>
<city>city name 7fc390f3-5570-408f-bba0-b4a157151678</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>ance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 4b7d64fa-39f4-445a-a668-b6a79991324a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography b6becad2-4c29-4c7e-98e0-211907a3834a</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 21</name>
<date>05/19/13</date>
<author>author name 7b4ff4d0-058e-4e11-97ea-de4a94536af8</author>
<city>city name 26a93ce8-83db-47c9-86a7-4b9c26501b79</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>kes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked ove</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ut I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close bec</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>ing to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think ab</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f9510c84-c5c5-407e-af84-9855f610fd6a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 4753b56f-ee38-41af-88f5-7023cb9de141</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 22</name>
<date>12/24/06</date>
<author>author name 6150b2f2-1421-49ad-a7d6-60f88418df89</author>
<city>city name b4165142-6820-4f71-800f-6d6e4af88029</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>e I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his repo</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>arter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 1ac1dfb7-bcea-485d-a65e-1191061f2463</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 1bd3123b-83b9-465e-af32-da5bf893b3eb</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 23</name>
<date>01/25/17</date>
<author>author name 935779ce-1897-4a86-8ae0-acd9119549fe</author>
<city>city name bd99c3c4-e343-41ca-b3bd-526f0a07ee44</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>owed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back t</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed hims</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source fdfe403f-7e4a-4745-bf63-9eb4b6441196</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 58f7523a-e576-43df-b41e-eeaad1518018</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 24</name>
<date>05/29/95</date>
<author>author name 9f2705e9-e827-4787-9c73-deb74db4c958</author>
<city>city name a0fc7e33-a046-4e54-a59b-d6aad832de6b</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>t on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 9f128a6b-f3ab-4e83-88a6-56fd9816d8eb</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 1907c67c-03ad-425e-9841-e4e91440591b</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 25</name>
<date>03/03/04</date>
<author>author name 6bd0bde5-10ae-44f2-b763-5e85b984913c</author>
<city>city name ca3b1203-578b-46fa-84c6-6a304dfba3a6</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>nections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text> he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these ge</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 58d7e223-bebb-41cd-af6f-dfeb2b5c0986</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography efa1ad71-9d84-4a4e-9cfe-f97b6bd3494d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 26</name>
<date>09/08/07</date>
<author>author name 5955c6ca-6cfe-44dd-b17e-8d952496c17f</author>
<city>city name 254f54ea-548b-45cb-b461-735cf6497ffa</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ing I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the b</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's wh</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 853ec3d6-622d-4916-926c-9a58eac16865</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography ad1be9d6-a1dd-4604-a9b1-5c26c4ba052d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 27</name>
<date>12/19/15</date>
<author>author name 617f34f4-7bfe-41b4-a707-b3b2085630af</author>
<city>city name 9174952b-5851-48f0-85de-27128afa60d1</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>een set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommendation not to make any claim as the doctor believed that no-one was ever ill but that many were workshy. And what's more, would he have b</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>hrough that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid hi</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>'s anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he re</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 931b6ce0-d7cf-4e02-9e15-607d35eb765d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 945acb92-7da2-460b-9197-261b2697a191</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 28</name>
<date>05/28/05</date>
<author>author name 4b8dfcc0-3d60-4c44-b956-314ab42ba622</author>
<city>city name 52bfe9fe-e828-487d-9261-d19cc1ff3d8d</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ead out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>rds the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source b65e24e2-9876-44ca-9124-db4448571caf</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 7eeb8561-dfc7-4704-929e-1146b0601947</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 29</name>
<date>02/05/97</date>
<author>author name a599fa6e-3320-4fd4-939e-f14c1182258d</author>
<city>city name 6ef80c25-b26f-4641-b0af-cf8b7884fe8d</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found wher</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 7f1581eb-75e5-4599-9cd0-668e12abc98f</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 4e18b85f-89f9-4ecf-b58b-701707153a65</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 30</name>
<date>12/20/01</date>
<author>author name d7b14542-0294-4315-95fb-246fd5ea63db</author>
<city>city name 8222d890-edb3-44a2-828e-8d0b408f2407</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unabl</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>nd fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>ur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the w</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f77f517c-270b-4e2e-9eff-af042bfa9210</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 9b6fc489-62ea-40d4-8c11-b8179d2fec68</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 31</name>
<date>09/10/14</date>
<author>author name ba57a128-b8ae-4fbf-a5ae-c33952af353f</author>
<city>city name 46942b30-1895-4ca7-97b9-631dccdd1df0</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>ll the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>r; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>ards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source eb624542-bd73-4796-91ab-caf0006dfb2f</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography e9d02a8d-6a72-48a2-9206-49d2653a78a9</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 32</name>
<date>05/27/10</date>
<author>author name a922b880-9c9c-4bd6-a7ea-5c9226f7b088</author>
<city>city name de11d9e7-fc42-40ae-8a9c-b4be02eb7e53</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>Gregor Samsa woke from troubled dreams, he found himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering l</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>n the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 3c80209e-a100-4da9-946f-48570e09abb1</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography e74f6fc7-e55e-4d65-a9a5-1244204e61d3</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 33</name>
<date>12/31/14</date>
<author>author name c48497d4-01e7-491e-b45c-38b235f533fc</author>
<city>city name c76b6a80-1486-4dfa-a719-8359f62964a4</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a l</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>"How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt bef</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous car</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source fac027da-edd2-47dd-b358-75295d201fd9</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography de49ece3-f483-4a19-bbb7-e61ec28d8dad</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 34</name>
<date>01/21/10</date>
<author>author name 11251b07-7f17-48b8-935d-1b7a8e756991</author>
<city>city name 85d38822-c8ef-466f-9768-ef6c5248dfb7</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>come friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the s</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>d better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 86246cf9-f7d8-4aa6-95ef-44c9966d33bc</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography b7892195-8196-4a01-a3c8-4df7a8768878</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 35</name>
<date>02/22/07</date>
<author>author name 894ed46e-70ec-4ab4-91c6-f1b605e61846</author>
<city>city name b15e6965-3e7e-4b1f-a906-cc7713acfc7f</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that wou</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on h</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ds the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white s</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 3381f32b-9643-4aee-adc0-997d86ba615d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 4dc77b2b-73f8-4dcd-a492-1648d2c7d9ab</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 36</name>
<date>08/04/97</date>
<author>author name 32083209-d399-4919-8ce1-0892ac9064e0</author>
<city>city name df7e7f93-32d7-40a3-b3a3-a640fec45424</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>y fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It c</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>re that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Tr</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>ll weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 7fa5b0cd-44bb-47fe-9f30-d265940e03ed</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography a5975d5f-e264-412f-8c99-2dcc72c13d98</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 37</name>
<date>07/15/02</date>
<author>author name dc548372-71a7-416d-be43-25b2ef433ebe</author>
<city>city name 2f05926b-77b1-42c7-be11-86c8416c32d9</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>old shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quie</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>ill sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text> house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't h</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>ts to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f736e918-2cd6-4b60-8587-d4f165616d97</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 2915b465-d1d2-4ae4-a17b-226a0651430e</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 38</name>
<date>07/12/04</date>
<author>author name 1d04b11a-307d-4de8-af23-4f039359b56d</author>
<city>city name 0c4b2a57-2498-423c-ad76-8447dd0bb303</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>in. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wou</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>sed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsen</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>ing he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tri</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 7f1ea281-ddb0-4809-ac5a-c0cf10706b05</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 681f951f-e70c-4faf-b76a-88a8d7f23527</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 39</name>
<date>08/09/96</date>
<author>author name ede6107b-f8df-4f7c-bd3d-b51add1a9396</author>
<city>city name c2019205-fdd5-4a8b-981d-a224c4f05952</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ore deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certain</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>port about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What abou</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The off</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>bout Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely str</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 0e707b22-8333-4df2-99e9-e0d0520dfe6c</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 28376a25-32cf-4110-bdb7-8a8c4e4e7588</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 40</name>
<date>04/15/00</date>
<author>author name fcd83692-be49-4685-a32e-dcad437266f2</author>
<city>city name 49f23f18-5da6-4457-8576-93681291cf34</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>nce, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text> there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 6164253f-94e4-43ae-bada-98b31dcaf925</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 99cd59f6-3661-4b62-99b4-6848c887c91d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 41</name>
<date>10/23/06</date>
<author>author name 573966ed-624d-465c-a01b-f132094215ed</author>
<city>city name 6a6b8b8d-deaa-46f8-96a8-af89b73f6122</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text>hat furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being t</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush l</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>initely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source dfa690a6-454a-4791-97b4-13871ce4e65a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography dd1e8b44-eb89-4058-ab99-1a98b729d5d0</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 42</name>
<date>03/16/04</date>
<author>author name 1c3a8aa2-6503-4d9c-b2ce-7fa2b9fc9ba5</author>
<city>city name f1b06aa9-f0d6-4f01-8128-bd0865829434</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>is legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text> with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>kfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 9fad6600-5560-4476-8eb1-e696eb24fe41</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 333c0ad6-52f4-4fe0-bf34-7da3ef5a588d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 43</name>
<date>04/11/07</date>
<author>author name 1b6700f8-6418-472b-84f4-8a4feb6f69f2</author>
<city>city name a2ff27ad-eef7-4c57-90f6-6822303477ee</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>d in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floun</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 6fe3c1ab-04ff-42db-8ad9-9e433e301c58</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography e1cf2a59-1321-4ea6-a6a5-979fe0c8a121</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 44</name>
<date>12/24/99</date>
<author>author name a39a201d-0b46-47f1-b817-a01d1f364ad4</author>
<city>city name a6184113-4fc5-404b-9638-760b16ef15e0</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy so</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source c66a2f47-f4c8-43e3-829f-80ab5adabc35</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography b63b8612-b46c-4169-8193-bdd48b010bba</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 45</name>
<date>06/28/16</date>
<author>author name e2b758c1-07e2-49f2-9172-d71a6fecebf2</author>
<city>city name b6193e7e-38c5-4a1e-b634-629ad6581650</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>n at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he di</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forward</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>hen I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clo</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>e-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f05764c9-c015-44be-9a26-96f6577d8464</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 98672695-f9c9-4f37-9560-3d352dd1c8d0</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 46</name>
<date>02/27/95</date>
<author>author name 6a178468-d883-4aee-8e5b-83c783733462</author>
<city>city name 41d294f5-fb1f-4cfa-aa4c-3ebbf3516ede</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>Samsa woke from troubled dreams, he found himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>he rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully b</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text> happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 5b9a1567-c515-45b6-a619-c3cfb09500f9</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 17cc6843-03e9-4d62-8c76-6cd83fe09ae3</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 47</name>
<date>06/13/06</date>
<author>author name 216ce72b-2e59-4432-8f85-cbd940ee8292</author>
<city>city name c83593a8-0cae-45c8-9ed1-ec773800f7b9</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the be</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to sev</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>is former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be t</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source dd8b3a4e-4e43-4639-be77-033c5b343534</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 248fe1a3-dbbf-4e64-93b8-1cd4d8b27996</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 48</name>
<date>03/30/12</date>
<author>author name ea28e899-ff32-44b2-85fa-e8728d131f04</author>
<city>city name 4a8f2b36-e4c5-4b36-a2ff-e061743db771</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> troubled dreams, he found himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt befo</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text>wed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text> who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into tha</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source a102e178-778a-4ccb-94ab-b21437e847d9</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 580fbf9a-2b37-4e97-9d07-68617485d8ff</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 49</name>
<date>11/09/99</date>
<author>author name 14df980b-d2a9-432c-8c69-8454ad46c807</author>
<city>city name e98fd133-e2f1-4a99-946e-627383f7b670</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more dee</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text>ould see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 537d0e20-5a00-449f-9dae-06347c0bb461</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 3e2fe46e-593a-4b4d-8417-61ee70683034</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 50</name>
<date>01/17/07</date>
<author>author name 6fbed642-88ca-4b41-8025-4aae2864e29e</author>
<city>city name b2925be3-b425-4d7b-aee4-77b3bd6acb7b</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>k, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommendation not to make any claim as the doctor believed that no-one was ever ill but that many were work</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were t</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f5c2bce5-38a9-4c40-8625-32272357bc98</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 20867c46-dcb1-496e-a3b9-36585c6dc3f9</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 51</name>
<date>04/17/06</date>
<author>author name cb1dc290-d90f-4b5d-bc9d-725d6993d421</author>
<city>city name 80603c1c-ae49-43f1-abc6-484b44c94f81</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ugh a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>ing salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 366a13f0-ac4f-49e5-8266-ffc9555efc5a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography e22ed37e-6b79-4756-a355-978f8f44c9bb</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 52</name>
<date>11/05/09</date>
<author>author name fa67d673-b7c8-44e8-8d86-6f633469910c</author>
<city>city name 4d4f4b04-cb83-4425-96d0-3512601bca5e</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>itted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stu</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>y fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head bett</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>itted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. Ho</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source ee45ae97-6318-41a2-9a03-82702e056a2e</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 80f86a4f-743a-4e73-818c-e49f525b1052</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 53</name>
<date>05/02/95</date>
<author>author name 84f0e573-b191-4cad-a7f1-6bb88606c815</author>
<city>city name 4d9826f4-48d0-4456-a673-d2053f088f49</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making t</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 8f11881f-50de-46c7-9bb4-b24b90e4409a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography c87da28f-f5e2-4c95-9715-5a6f08edad71</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 54</name>
<date>05/27/96</date>
<author>author name 119b97de-7042-4db2-adff-c36f8f266ed8</author>
<city>city name 2b601541-ae96-4ef4-af44-e7e21ee58783</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ied to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>t, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I thin</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text> given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. H</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source b1e6c22d-cac8-4712-9e29-1947b8895572</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 20a3e8ca-5f8e-4945-b5d6-531b5f194c3a</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 55</name>
<date>03/18/95</date>
<author>author name 4ae448ca-7721-4cf5-a70b-f9d0e70a9074</author>
<city>city name 3b7253b3-c918-486e-b7e9-d0e6eae59ce7</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>hat's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text> seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to q</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>ugh, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 2245cfda-7a2b-4f4a-8a3d-d77eca34870c</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 040d28b9-1928-4a2d-b8ac-c307b16d8d06</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 56</name>
<date>01/07/05</date>
<author>author name 7a1dd020-0966-4c7e-8561-bbec53025122</author>
<city>city name 745f1489-aa32-47e8-a262-e690ffcf97c7</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ome friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers.</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text> go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source ee3f8627-fb44-415a-8382-4d01447e9192</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 1f279f42-9b2c-45c0-93b6-481e0c057b3c</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 57</name>
<date>09/10/11</date>
<author>author name 356300e8-005e-427f-8cb6-a0af2c97320b</author>
<city>city name 68680d5a-8b51-48c3-be4f-4783150d53c4</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text> However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's t</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ps of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 4f2b3af6-5292-4182-b669-fe4819abc6e6</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 25c1e4b4-75ba-4eb0-a27b-15c731e7f9bd</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 58</name>
<date>06/22/02</date>
<author>author name 7e0e0f4e-ed7e-4cf0-bbae-23bc3c8c97e2</author>
<city>city name 608f3bd5-db61-4918-96ad-ecff40bd951c</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>y all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your des</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text> out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>'t have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source faab2d58-62a2-48fe-b768-4074994cc945</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 51f9b7b7-2a65-4bd7-9f17-24d218d619ab</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 59</name>
<date>10/06/11</date>
<author>author name d2478d6d-9132-4153-91df-29374181949a</author>
<city>city name 56d77229-b0d4-4462-ae68-13b3903d58d2</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know ju</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text> me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd ha</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ese gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 5f02c3e5-2214-46a1-acc2-b800188143ee</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 48a5ae08-05df-4427-89cd-52b4215a1265</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 60</name>
<date>07/04/03</date>
<author>author name 9afbc522-f00a-43b7-ab86-28e34d1f4282</author>
<city>city name 694e18e8-88b7-4fab-ac60-d54a4a1ddbc7</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>as, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I thin</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>on. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentle</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Oth</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source bfeb8a64-002b-4e29-b6c1-dea9b8f7d630</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 57bfbc8d-e0c8-438f-96f9-d88b1e5458e2</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 61</name>
<date>09/26/09</date>
<author>author name 66eb0b41-5c6d-4a22-919c-b6d4bbbaec8c</author>
<city>city name e28d0459-1dc2-480c-a150-04a617da192c</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>d to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinat</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>ract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source c6ace75b-c96a-4fbf-9a37-ebf30cf38eb9</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 29b9c02b-96c4-49c5-b175-344826b8a49b</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 62</name>
<date>07/09/15</date>
<author>author name 2241b652-87b6-48bb-a514-0bed0be1182c</author>
<city>city name 542ba9cc-59ae-4658-a2eb-fecff12e36ce</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>e. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sle</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur mu</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>ower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be hear</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source bd15cb27-2d9c-4176-8674-826fdc49ef5d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 8bd409f2-6143-471b-bc52-040d95191b2c</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 63</name>
<date>03/15/08</date>
<author>author name 9cc52795-30c1-4bcf-a7cf-90d6db21f488</author>
<city>city name 6c3d8793-029c-4b3e-843c-a7f87ac97126</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommendation not to make any claim as the doctor believed that no-one was ever ill but that many were workshy. And what's more, would he have been entire</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>ing. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round wi</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source e3562cc7-9c98-4328-b7be-4196e294558a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 2cec32e1-4cb8-47ce-968e-7bf11859b943</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 64</name>
<date>03/21/08</date>
<author>author name 9fa835ed-6d53-418e-8cf5-c156aef7b8f4</author>
<city>city name caf4d2a7-7bb2-4920-9d71-56605f5706e9</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covere</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, an</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he ha</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source ebcf44f5-986b-4fce-b76f-fdc93dc3af6c</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 864a5c2e-7aba-4bad-a11b-3f791f5495bb</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 65</name>
<date>06/23/06</date>
<author>author name 87ea3237-66a0-4faf-a1ab-668e806b1233</author>
<city>city name f159283a-dfa2-479d-aa47-3fc7d2af9023</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ed magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he d</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed hims</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source c7214c4d-5097-4c8b-ad9d-a21174cd9060</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 59d6fb92-31a0-4e21-b075-1681bbf63b3b</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 66</name>
<date>07/28/05</date>
<author>author name 293b6cf6-ec2d-4a46-a810-462548462516</author>
<city>city name 0f61ddc9-42a6-44c0-bc09-b3265936f843</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>ard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 1b8d1b84-3880-46a8-88d5-86f200256efd</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 4338636f-1099-460f-af39-3508b3b5a670</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 67</name>
<date>10/05/14</date>
<author>author name 854db514-103d-439e-b32f-e097b77aa52d</author>
<city>city name 567bf7f6-58f1-420c-9012-7d30eb10561a</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money to</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>asts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him ju</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source fbbcf378-bec3-4955-a909-9dc68730aad0</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography d1fd7fdb-19a1-47cb-ae0b-4cc1fc2a4023</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 68</name>
<date>10/30/00</date>
<author>author name 0e40d5f3-2015-4dbb-a240-12d5dba99028</author>
<city>city name a2de7ed1-54fe-4b18-b35d-b2b7935f6959</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ou can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all th</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>h up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source d50fb529-1ee6-41fe-9d30-0eafe1fa2838</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography bddb3bb4-4612-49a4-988e-7f77439b6ea7</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 69</name>
<date>07/03/01</date>
<author>author name a0ec6e8b-a7a6-4237-aa02-f870e5adf2df</author>
<city>city name 7160dceb-18b6-4c9f-80bd-0db737e867b4</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift h</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>dow at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his ey</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 457e7fc7-c20d-4d67-917e-abc9bf725610</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 67461614-f1f9-44df-8f09-d12210006664</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 70</name>
<date>04/01/99</date>
<author>author name 669d835b-6f36-47e0-9cc0-ac154b7348f2</author>
<city>city name 0810cb8b-5e13-4dd5-b303-a4008ed3a2ff</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>t is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talkin</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>f; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source dc79812e-7f3f-4715-bd43-60a10f844063</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography bb9afc01-9a41-474d-849b-aad08480b97a</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 71</name>
<date>07/31/04</date>
<author>author name e0eb126e-eb86-4e25-83a7-0a3e76e9223a</author>
<city>city name 68757e97-9f1f-4285-86f2-6ba8828b45b7</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>e of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was somethi</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>dy fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made hi</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 26f36a13-2e46-438f-a317-1f725732596a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography d8bc82e7-f5f1-4849-af0b-3f751fba1b6e</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 72</name>
<date>06/21/01</date>
<author>author name ccb2d0cb-acd4-4f06-9e80-5ae663f78f6c</author>
<city>city name 873ab25b-d2a9-42ce-93ed-13077e8df006</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was some</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>h a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which ma</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>s he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesma</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source b8f612e6-7cb5-4812-8415-eaa799e0025d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 27a9ac59-910a-4b6c-8936-67e9a676eef5</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 73</name>
<date>09/06/96</date>
<author>author name 69d8ef09-e85b-4dcb-ab22-d77f4461aca0</author>
<city>city name 9daa824d-040c-4e07-a15b-2675d871f8b4</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>yone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>ould be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him e</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text> up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text>tle white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid ba</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 6eac95d7-127b-482d-ad0e-2ae839bf11fa</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography e977aa57-f066-4101-a8a3-fbaa5cbe925c</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 74</name>
<date>11/07/00</date>
<author>author name 6a1e152e-85e5-4cd1-ac46-01744ef4cf02</author>
<city>city name 327e532c-ff03-45d4-9c8c-8a84a02612b2</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>tting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insuran</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>alf past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep throu</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>amples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source e4562095-97a6-4ca1-9b14-6ff5875ae288</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 5bf59a37-809f-4067-8341-eb741abd3e3d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 75</name>
<date>08/29/11</date>
<author>author name e8ea9f04-3683-40cb-b278-5dce621d895e</author>
<city>city name 8a1f93d7-172b-4d5a-8cb0-2929437106a2</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text> He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>hese gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 338ca3c7-9436-4e4e-aa35-76dcc53734f1</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography b005a363-431a-423c-9cd4-dcef95e9b317</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 76</name>
<date>02/13/16</date>
<author>author name afa72199-3c1d-4b83-bfff-0de87d7b09c1</author>
<city>city name bb4e031b-fd0f-477b-b135-cea50c29b111</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text> with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, b</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quit</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text> lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but tha</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 45a6cf17-6f03-434e-ba70-8f21c05e68fe</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 0ffba6b7-9990-4f73-8886-a4bc7ad73737</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 77</name>
<date>02/06/13</date>
<author>author name 4a683d68-46b8-4426-8c0e-49fe3c81aaaf</author>
<city>city name 27024c3c-5068-49a7-8170-efcb42ad078f</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>lling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots o</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>e with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 01ae7300-555e-4790-b1f2-503a0f2c61e6</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography b5f59384-1a36-4ae9-974b-229119dafdd3</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 78</name>
<date>11/01/97</date>
<author>author name 3bea6003-f110-4c53-b2ab-8eedaa13ed2f</author>
<city>city name 0b46ac1d-830c-4962-8f35-4a2169557d3e</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>lt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text> contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become fr</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source da52e5ae-9cf9-49d1-9a28-063843a9264d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 65b8e4a3-5369-494a-9ac7-52d8b3227543</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 79</name>
<date>06/15/10</date>
<author>author name 17c48f6d-65e5-49de-814f-ad246bbf78cc</author>
<city>city name 37c0e1be-8b6c-4565-b62d-5dfb993d28e3</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>own belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a st</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>he window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that positi</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source a1d513f2-9115-44a6-b9ae-f891f61e73d8</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography a2c5c204-a90c-416c-a91b-8a93019a90ee</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 80</name>
<date>12/19/11</date>
<author>author name 92409788-b0ea-40bc-9054-6e11d55fd432</author>
<city>city name 8ffd2289-0ec9-43bf-a9d4-e7a280e2b6d4</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>f all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not pa</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>cefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samp</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have t</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as i</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 58bd7f9f-3d1e-4f90-929a-c0f5633681b3</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 9d70c7e3-2a9b-4ba2-b948-f1645f9aade3</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 81</name>
<date>03/12/08</date>
<author>author name bfe51dc0-6d3d-4d75-a338-ee3b19be14e5</author>
<city>city name 1a23c7bf-2f42-4d92-8100-21486c8b03b7</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>htly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there h</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>ht. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection o</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 55681f7c-04bf-49bf-bab4-8be7ae270505</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 001bb97f-5e2d-4690-a603-9b5a841bad41</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 82</name>
<date>10/05/02</date>
<author>author name 8badd377-cd33-40c0-b492-2f773967e467</author>
<city>city name 81ab70da-86c4-49b4-abd8-35c75677b92d</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>inates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put i</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>ter than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #5</name><text>through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text> noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as t</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 98db92fb-78d1-4cd1-8558-056b63bdd22d</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 61db0993-8b62-4d52-901d-91373deb199d</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 83</name>
<date>10/06/16</date>
<author>author name f46811fb-fc0e-4ade-8aa1-ad41207f8539</author>
<city>city name aa860e39-590f-49d2-bf4c-fdb0f94a0d45</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ed frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He sl</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>re effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found wh</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source f35d588a-0e7d-4b91-8f28-3359e56e236e</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 47620793-d92e-4715-9458-f72252112066</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 84</name>
<date>11/03/09</date>
<author>author name 6d829619-f388-4f53-b17d-ad25c58526ce</author>
<city>city name bd8bc3f0-a63a-483d-b924-60059b287c27</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>t on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stoppe</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>ad recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source a437d46f-23fb-4d02-86c0-cb633aaa25f7</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 11525ca1-59d8-4c88-83f1-708c4ee01033</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 85</name>
<date>03/04/17</date>
<author>author name 87985e6d-c4f3-4c0b-9671-75db291ce6d0</author>
<city>city name 36aba615-445a-4e83-b0ab-868954913f91</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommendation not to make any claim as the doctor believed that no-one was ever ill but that many were workshy. And what's more, would he have been entirely wrong in this case? Grego</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>een ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 48271471-c10d-446f-b2ae-764a59dad584</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 4c5330b9-d36d-4ab2-b3cf-ab5330bfc7b9</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 86</name>
<date>08/27/07</date>
<author>author name 9cc34d15-d1a2-4d01-ba75-aa9e16730bc6</author>
<city>city name 540d03d1-2464-4945-b382-2a0b05001868</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>e all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text>ck towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which h</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 4842927f-e1fc-41d8-85ef-75b712b59c51</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 2cc049a1-8ac9-4d46-b272-d3a359b532aa</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 87</name>
<date>04/29/97</date>
<author>author name 7bef2b4d-6ef9-4609-aee8-1dec56f90564</author>
<city>city name 0456df6c-d3cf-4285-a22b-b11eaaac1808</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>d out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries a</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text> on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an i</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #9</name><text>d be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. H</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 77da976b-d664-46f8-9b6d-6c88c74f28f6</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 3884aeca-63d4-4a2f-aa77-28b4edc1b4cc</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 88</name>
<date>03/28/96</date>
<author>author name 95880021-7904-4f8a-aee0-17f61c8e30e5</author>
<city>city name 3bb98043-d083-47be-b714-a0a2bb483dfb</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked. "What's happened to me?" he thought. It wasn't a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text> room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the </text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source c317ad1b-755f-4849-bdba-13c0fb5d4683</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography dfa62660-8e30-4899-9f36-fe7909e4fee2</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 89</name>
<date>04/03/02</date>
<author>author name 501b2a32-9298-4527-bdbc-8a13bd8f6bf8</author>
<city>city name ceb79f96-64d2-4b57-af11-2d1ab6d1b404</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>k, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>l, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at fi</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #11</name><text>ving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 12cf82b3-f10c-4999-b695-f0ff793ef2a7</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography d958470c-3e63-4d91-916b-d99019329262</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 90</name>
<date>01/18/04</date>
<author>author name 32ec17c6-69f5-4bce-b978-4e58b758a401</author>
<city>city name 36bad56f-2a24-49f0-98a0-7c2b811e2abd</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>t I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; </text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text> hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's defin</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>hat I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 55c978ad-f1b9-415c-9db9-cd3722d0dd7e</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 179d0473-d5c0-4e8d-b1c3-63c2b2f9e404</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 91</name>
<date>04/16/01</date>
<author>author name ef6c7db6-72ff-4ae8-990a-004aec1b09b1</author>
<city>city name afb52c18-cf2a-4b22-bd39-7b66cb874b7b</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ad never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating t</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>ons, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 40019758-61d9-4e49-bf99-124ff524a9fd</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 985662ec-9660-44d7-952e-b4668b252694</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 92</name>
<date>09/11/01</date>
<author>author name fe9daed2-7bf4-4694-ac32-72c29883333a</author>
<city>city name 81849be9-c7ce-4d06-8383-a79b793e2a75</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business t</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text> business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, c</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell h</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source c78882d0-5084-4a6c-8fc5-65af74d8a381</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 897057e2-a7de-4be0-8349-699b7a3a9ccf</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 93</name>
<date>06/26/04</date>
<author>author name 0184edf9-004e-418a-a4f7-af5d2fccde8c</author>
<city>city name 14f70ad2-fbee-4a3a-8f1d-e414d4f9ee18</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ain went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommendation not to make any claim as the doctor be</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text> catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #4</name><text>esh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 686353ca-a754-4658-b327-4d97e8ea8751</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography f64b1c50-d0d9-4bdb-8c9b-67d445cc16fd</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 94</name>
<date>06/01/02</date>
<author>author name a4d8d49d-1f45-4b39-9704-746f536377ad</author>
<city>city name b77c1372-ca21-4546-b4fa-28c276eae873</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>d out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text> suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text> him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll </text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #10</name><text> clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel p</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 26387829-1927-4d12-862d-afb798d2b8a7</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 8be7f3b1-0779-49f2-b99e-3382c69be163</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 95</name>
<date>12/22/07</date>
<author>author name e8f16735-fa7b-4e3f-93d8-bac6b71ca658</author>
<city>city name b6177508-4075-4894-8eb4-3aca0aaf00ab</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his b</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #2</name><text>areer it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doi</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse o</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source 1ce23d3d-39f4-4d22-a5be-95948bb1ca93</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography c37f7e0a-ef64-4778-8e12-acda559b45df</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 96</name>
<date>06/09/15</date>
<author>author name 34df06e5-68f7-4a36-88e3-77da615fa091</author>
<city>city name 7fdcfd50-66d1-463b-a31a-43cba164d5e4</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>light itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! And it's a funny sort of business to be sitting up there at your desk, talking down at your subordinates from up there, especially when you have to go right up close because the boss is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - ano</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #7</name><text>ck to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, le</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source d56dfffe-528e-4311-8117-e88b3518c8aa</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography e01f57cf-0a3c-4756-b9bf-33c471274b5c</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 97</name>
<date>10/16/98</date>
<author>author name 7e7cf845-977c-4fbf-82d9-f6c492af06ab</author>
<city>city name da983d54-24b9-465a-b02d-5092e8599b30</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract, these gentlemen are always still sitting there eating their breakfasts. I ought to just try that with my boss; I'd get kicked out on the spot. But who knows, maybe that would be the best thing for me. If I didn't have my parents to think about I'd have given in my notice a long time ago, I'd have gone up to the boss and told him just what I think, tell him everything I would, let him know just what I feel. He'd fall right off his desk! An</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #1</name><text>e itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source cb77d939-2b72-40e5-9d89-491549918f2a</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 5dd319d5-4de9-4931-9207-c603bbf8f6c4</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 98</name>
<date>06/24/03</date>
<author>author name 77f4aca3-ef66-4135-91a6-a07bb68609c9</author>
<city>city name 9b530623-f68e-4c61-8971-122563f088c7</city>
<country>UK</country>
<text>ps of rain could be heard hitting the pane, which made him feel quite sad. "How about if I sleep a little bit longer and forget all this nonsense", he thought, but that was something he was unable to do because he was used to sleeping on his right, and in his present state couldn't get into that position. However hard he threw himself onto his right, he always rolled back to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at home, and on top of that there's the curse of travelling, worries about making train connections, bad and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with one of his legs he drew it quickly back because as soon as he touched it he was overcome by a cold shudder. He slid back into his former position. "Getting up early all the time", he thought, "it makes you stupid. You've got to get enough sleep. Other travelling salesmen live a life of luxury. For instance, whenever I go back to the guest house during the morning to copy out the contract</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>and irregular food, contact with different people all the time so that you can never get to know anyone or become friendly with them. It can all go to Hell!" He felt a slight itch up on his belly; pushed himself slowly up on his back towards the headboard so that he could lift his head better; found where the itch was, and saw that it was covered with lots of little white spots which he didn't know what to make of; and when he tried to feel the place with o</text></tactic>
<tactic><name>Tactic #6</name><text>to where he was. He must have tried it a hundred times, shut his eyes so that he wouldn't have to look at the floundering legs, and only stopped when he began to feel a mild, dull pain there that he had never felt before. "Oh, God", he thought, "what a strenuous career it is that I've chosen! Travelling day in and day out. Doing business like this takes much more effort than doing your own business at hom</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source abd65678-5c22-44a3-889e-69ebc3e3a563</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 864a4c08-9302-4e2f-8f1f-55ebdbb4b5b8</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 99</name>
<date>09/05/98</date>
<author>author name 38fbed7f-d10a-475f-ad97-633aee5bc45a</author>
<city>city name 3762d79a-42a6-4843-91a5-2973214aa956</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text>ock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did cat</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #8</name><text>that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung.</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source b0c92a2d-70f5-43ef-9853-f433092a4537</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography 94196b39-f933-4977-9253-dac7f4283e42</bibl>
</excuse><excuse>
<name>excuse name 100</name>
<date>10/12/06</date>
<author>author name d85d5b31-c3f1-4cb6-bc14-c584bf4f17f3</author>
<city>city name 8bce7f28-6db7-4d15-862e-fa9c5ecdeee7</city>
<country>USA</country>
<text> is hard of hearing. Well, there's still some hope; once I've got the money together to pay off my parents' debt to him - another five or six years I suppose - that's definitely what I'll do. That's when I'll make the big change. First of all though, I've got to get up, my train leaves at five." And he looked over at the alarm clock, ticking on the chest of drawers. "God in Heaven!" he thought. It was half past six and the hands were quietly moving forwards, it was even later than half past, more like quarter to seven. Had the alarm clock not rung? He could see from the bed that it had been set for four o'clock as it should have been; it certainly must have rung. Yes, but was it possible to quietly sleep through that furniture-rattling noise? True, he had not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And even if he did catch the train he would not avoid his boss's anger as the office assistant would have been there to see the five o'clock train go, he would have put in his report about Gregor's not being there a long time ago. The office assistant was the boss's man, spineless, and with no understanding. What about if he reported sick? But that would be extremely strained and suspicious as in fifteen years of service Gregor had never once yet been ill. His boss would certainly come round with the doctor from the medical insurance company, accuse his parents of having a lazy son, and accept the doctor's recommendation not to make any claim as the doctor belie</text>
<tactics>
<tactic><name>Tactic #3</name><text> not slept peacefully, but probably all the more deeply because of that. What should he do now? The next train went at seven; if he were to catch that he would have to rush like mad and the collection of samples was still not packed, and he did not at all feel particularly fresh and lively. And</text></tactic>
</tactics>
<sources>
<source>source ddcf9db9-6bd0-4fc3-a971-4a3f15ef020b</source>
</sources>
<bibl>biliography c5026d62-91ab-4461-bca8-28d5c02bd605</bibl>
    </excuse>
</excuses>